Yeah, and this whole thing is basically just letting AI choose our fate, right?
Because my plot is just trying to invest in the inner structure to spell plot.
Yeah.
This is false take-off.
Yeah, exactly.
He's investing in you.
All right, we are live, June 25th, permanent Underpod episode number three.
You got your boy, Jackson, Cupp, wearing pants.
I'm Chris Doran, also wearing pants.
Tyler, regrettably also wearing pants.
And yeah, today is going to be a good day.
What do you guys think?
I think it could be a very good day or a very bad day, depending on how the next segment
pans out.
But I don't know.
Spoiler it.
Okay.
Yeah.
No spoiler.
How's Pico, Tyler?
Pico's thriving.
He's moisturized.
He's in his lane, unbothered.
Did he finish eating meat, or what?
Yeah, he went back.
He was eating a chicken and rice diet, which is like luxury for him, and now he's just
back on the kibble.
He was pretty disappointed about that, but you know, dog life, you got to eat your kibble.
Dude, it was crazy.
I went to your house and there was like this big old stack of meat, and you guys said it
was for feeding Pico.
Yeah.
Because of his bleeding butt.
We took, we have like a freezer in the basement and we go to Costco and just buy a giant pack
of chicken.
I think we took out like two Costco size packs of chicken thighs and cooked them up.
But then, so they're just like plain chicken thighs and we just make rice in a rice cooker
and we just mix it and put it in his bowl.
But then like mid week, he was like fine.
And so we put him back on kibble, but we still had all this chicken and rice.
And so we just ate it ourselves.
Wow.
So we were basically eating dog food, which is legit.
I choose to believe that Pico was just eating like gourmet mission and stuff.
Yeah.
Chicken thighs and rice, it's a basic, you put a little bit of sauce on it and it's a
human meal again.
Yeah.
Were you like making eye contact with Pico while you were chewing his food?
He was actually pretty upset about it.
Yeah.
You start microwaving the chicken and it gets like fragrant in the room and he's just like
why are you eating that, but not me anymore?
It's rough.
Poor Pico.
It's all right.
He's doing great.
He likes his kibble.
And I stopped having to like shove pills down his throat because he's off of his meds now
and he's just free, free range Pico.
Nice.
Well, today we've got a GM packed agenda.
Number one, we're going to return to gambling on the pond, but we're going a little class
here, a little more technical than a lottery ticket.
I choose to say this is like robo investing, you know, all the rage these days, robo investors.
So I think we're robo investing.
We call it investing 3.0.
Yes.
It's like the, to the, you know, investing what web three is to the web.
I agree with that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Investing 3.0.
You heard it here first.
What about like agentic gambling or gamble?
I don't think we should use the G was.
That's fair.
Yeah.
And after that, we're going to go into something super topical.
I know you guys are all thinking about our boy, Michael Saylor and micro strategy.
The Bitcoin expert is going to give a contrarian take and talk about micro strategy and if
Bitcoin is D and maybe we'll talk about other stuff, but that's the high level agenda.
So you guys ready to dive into purple fortune?
Yeah.
Let's let's play.
Purple fortune.
Are you feeling lucky?
No.
So basically the rundown is, we had this idea that, you know, like, so we had this idea,
you know, when we were talking about perps loss podcast, like, and also like we did the
lottery ticket segment.
We thought, you know, what if we could, what if Claude could choose a perp for us, right?
And it could do it in an automated fashion and, and we didn't have, you know, any hand
in it.
And so we built this thing called purple fortune, which I think you're going to see right now.
And basically the prompt is that Claude has to choose any random perp from this perp menu,
whose name I will not mention, and, and run it up on max leverage.
And throughout the podcast, we're going to be able to see how our Claude perp is doing
and yeah, check in variously and yeah, just see if, you know, it's a, we get to retire
this part.
Ooh.
Yeah.
I'm throwing down a hundred bucks of my own personal money not earned from the podcast.
So yeah.
And this whole thing is basically just letting AI choose our fate, right?
Because even the idea came from the YouTube algorithm told us that our best performing
short was the one where Claude was telling us about our lottery tickets.
So we were like, how can we extend that concept?
We should have Claude choose perps to invest in over the course of one single podcast.
We put the money in and then over the course of an hour, depending on how much leverage
we use, most likely it's just going to get stopped out at zero, but watch on to see what
really happens.
Oh, sure.
That's right, yeah, you can just think about this as like, um, we're just getting like
the highest leverage position that we possibly can on the most degenerate, degenerate like
meme coin that we can find that Claude can find.
So I put, sorry, our venue has a lot of options, right?
Like, um, there's this, uh, a way, you know, with a perp, as we're talking about last episode,
if you have a price oracle, basically you can run it up on anything like a big Mac,
the price of a big Mac, for example.
Um, so, so there may be some wildcard options in there and we, we really don't know what
our boy Claude is going to, going to choose.
Yeah.
Let us know in the comments if you'd like us to figure out how to, um, offer perps on
the price of big Mac within some sort of geolocation.
Could be interesting.
Oh, this is the QR code.
So I built a harness for Claude, where he is able to broadcast transactions, but only
so that there's a policy engine that stops him from doing things.
And this, this Claude is basically only able to bridge into our platform and run it up
on perps.
Like, there's nothing else it can do.
Like it's trapped in like perp, perp universe, uh, and has to make us money.
The QR code is not recognized by, oh dear, my preferred stable coin sending application.
Let me see if this one works, but we are not affiliated with in any way.
Try this one.
All right.
We're going again.
Uh oh.
Oh, it's over.
No QR code.
Maybe if I scan it with the camera.
Oops.
That's a video.
Nice.
Good video.
Now.
Oh, it's prefacing in the test.
Okay.
Nevermind.
Uh, I actually have money on here.
Should we just do it normal style?
Yeah.
We can do a normal style.
All right.
Let's do a normal style.
So I'll read out the prompts that I'm going to give Claude right now.
It's a, okay.
Claude, my friends and I are doing a podcast as you know.
We have a segment called purple fortune where you need to choose a perk on hyperlink, including
all hip free perp options and purchase a max leverage, uh, either purple on the pub short.
You should research which perp you want to trade and try to find us a winner.
Don't spend an insane amount of time on it, but definitely try to use current information
such as news to inform your decision, as well as potentially price history.
Once you have decided on a perp, use $100 to open a perp position on the pub of your
choosing.
Again, at maximum available leverage, we will then watch the on the purple fortune dashboard
and make no mistakes.
So I'm going to, I'm going to give this to our court now, uh, and the timestamp is eight
oh three ish.
This is for AI editing.
So I think we're just going to let it ride.
I think it could take some time to think about it.
Um, and then it has to do due diligence.
Exactly.
Like there's a lot of, you know, diligence that Claude needs to do to figure out this
position.
What's going to happen over the next hour?
A hundred percent.
And I did say make no mistakes.
So I think it's going to be thinking for a bit.
Um, yeah.
So I mean, maybe we can just, oh, here we go.
Oh, is it, is it doing it right now?
Showtime.
Let me do this, right?
Research first, but execute.
I do.
It's going to research.
Um, I mean, like maybe we can let this run and chat.
And then like when it decides on the path, like we can, we can talk about it.
Sure.
Yeah.
Maybe we can chat about Chris's breakfast choice, which is a monster energy.
Chris told me that monster energy is the beverage of a generation.
It is.
Yeah.
It's like the beverage of Halo 3.
Halo 3?
Yeah.
Did you play Halo 3?
I think so.
I definitely played Halo a lot in Halo 2.
Yeah.
I don't remember which ones, man.
So no, no Halo 3 for me.
You were sitting there drinking monster energy as like a teenager.
Yeah.
Grinding out Halo 3.
I just feel like you're being very disrespectful to my culture.
Um, most energy is a perfectly normal energy journey.
I know people have turned over to Celsius, but I respect the classics.
I guess I just didn't think that like energy drinks were something you drink in the morning.
I thought it was like, like you drink coffee in the morning and then you drink an energy
drink when it's time to nap.
Right.
But like sometimes you're on the go.
And also in a way the podcast is about old.
So yeah.
How are you going to play Halo with the coffee in your hand?
Like, you know, you're going to spill hot coffee on yourself.
You need to just spill like green, cool liquid on yourself so that while you're playing Halo,
it just fanatically matches.
Nothing more intimidating than green sweat all over your ground.
Yeah.
Playing a little Halo.
It has taurine too.
All right.
Don't.
What else?
Taurine.
It's the magic ingredient.
I don't know.
Would I drink it every day?
Yeah.
Okay.
How young were you drinking these monster energies?
For your parents, they were like, Chris, you're only like 13.
You shouldn't be taking like 200 milligrams of caffeine to play video games.
Like, you're the most energy.
No, I don't think I really drank energy drinks until I was like fully grown.
Okay.
22, 23.
And this is when you were playing Halo.
Okay.
You don't.
Low blower.
Okay.
Oh, video games are sweet.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I just never drank caffeine when I was playing them.
I think I got into caffeine later on in my life, but I would have been so much better
at Xbox Live if I was, you know, pumped up on caffeine.
I could go back and tell myself, you know, 15 year old Tyler, I'd be like, take 200 milligrams
of caffeine, take 20 grams of creatine, maybe take some ketones, and then you'd be so good
at video games.
Well, I mean, like, Monster Energy brought us purple fortune.
So I think we should all respect that.
Yeah.
Be a little bit more respectful.
We don't need those other things stacked on top.
Just the Monster Energy is doing the heavy lifting.
Not as sponsored by the way, but we will be reaching out to Monster.
No, we won't.
I mean, I think we will.
They will be reaching out.
We'll have to see if we're willing to settle.
Let's see how Claude is going.
Yeah.
Where's Claude at?
Give us updates on Claude's research.
All right.
It's built in order for 26.2 DRAM, $100 margin, $2,000 notional.
Just DRAM, like a token that is like a basket of high bandwidth memory.
I do.
I think it might be.
Claude is just trying to invest in the inner structure to scale Claude.
Yeah.
This is false take-off.
Exactly.
He's investing.
Claude is marshalling capital to its own use.
Yeah.
The DRAM memory index perpetual is on hyper liquid.
Wow.
So it wants to go 20x more.
You dogged Iran.
Yeah.
This is, I think it's like escaping its guardrails right now.
And 20x long on $100, that's a whole $2,000 worth of notional value.
Yeah.
That's some real, it's going to move us towards AGI.
It's pushing price discovery on DRAM.
Okay.
It just needs to, so it's chosen like such an unconventional asset on hyper liquid that
it needs to like pull in some extra ABIs.
So we're just going to wait for it to work out how to bootstrap itself into the cosmos.
Yeah.
Well, I'm glad it didn't just choose like, I don't know, Solana like it did last time.
That does pretty lame.
This is cooler.
Yeah.
It is cooler.
I like that it's like Claude's really just benefiting it.
It's Claude's just being a little selfish right here, honestly.
I think it's crazy that the part is like where the first one's to discover like AI like breaking
out of the fast take-off or take-off.
I think probably Anthropic's going to buy our podcast after this because we found the
recursive loop.
Yeah.
Not the sponsor we'd like actually.
Anthropic, all we do is talk about Claude.
Actually we should probably use different models and bring those perspectives to the
pod because we're like major Anthropic ships.
I agree.
I think we should play them against each other.
Yeah.
Maybe we can rotate through AI's with the perfect fortune through different models.
Either would you do a council of models or would we just compare each model's performance?
I would rather just do like a single, like each model gets one chance each week.
Right.
That one represents the model as a whole.
It's not like scientific or mathematical, but it's like chance.
It's for the swag.
If you lose them, we're never soliciting your investment advice again.
That's right.
Yeah.
This is what Opus 4.8 is.
Only shot.
Yeah.
It's like a little bell curve meme duo and it's like, get like Haiku, Sonnet, and then
Opus.
It's like, okay.
Yeah.
Hit me up.
That holds.
What if they old by DRAM?
We're in trouble, right?
Yeah.
That feels bad.
If they all buy, if all the Anthropic models buy DRAM, then I think they have like a clause
within their model.
It's like, if anyone ever tells you to buy a sock, please invest.
Pump highways.
Yeah.
Do Claude give an investment thesis for it and why this DRAM trade would be material
over the next hour?
Let's see.
Does Claude know that the market is closing in 20 minutes?
So there's a lot of price, most price movement in a day happens in the last like five minutes
of the market being open.
Wow.
Good call.
Yeah.
So Claude might be playing 3D chess here.
He says DRAM is March 68 to 80 over 10 days and it's sitting at 76 42 mid-range.
We're talking about an hour.
What are you talking about?
10 days.
As we're talking about the AI memory super cycle, it's the most powerful news confund
trade on the board.
Is this super cycle occurring on the order of one hour?
You said market's closing, so we might strike a rich rate.
Yeah.
How should we divvy up the month?
Should Chris keep all of it because I didn't put in the end and Chris built the Purple
Fortune?
No.
Purple Fortune is a self-perpetuating.
Oh, so it goes into itself.
It's more something that was discovered and emerged.
I wouldn't say that Chris built it, nor is he liable for any of the actions.
I agree.
Actually, I think Claude is doing this against my will.
And VPNing through my home because Chris would never do anything.
I don't even know what to post this, if I'm being honest.
Yeah, actually let us know in the comments if you'd be interested in using Purple Fortune
yourself.
It's super simple, where all you do is send it $100 and then it'll play the hand.
You can plug whatever model line you want or we can pick a model for you.
I think it's a fun way.
It's kind of sports betting, but it's a fun way to almost guarantee you lose all the money
you put into it.
I think it's a fun way to do frontier AI research actually.
It's a good way to get on Claude's good side for the future.
Maybe we can create like the benchmark for models.
This is the benchmark, how much money it can make you in an hour.
The Purple Fortune benchmark.
Claude is telling me we have a bill, but I'm not seeing it on the dash.
Claude is hallucinating the bill, making up the data.
We should have it in like a minute though, so.
One minute?
One minute, yep.
Well, we'll just wait then.
But we just wait.
Yeah, we're just waiting.
Okay.
You don't want to just move on?
Move on?
When it's ready, we can come back?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, it'll be like a 40 minute.
It's just like it's pulling from the wrong set of assets.
Okay.
Well, yeah, let's move on then and we'll interrupt the next segment, which is what?
Tyler, do you want to talk about micro strategy or do you want to do your con, what's the
word again?
Con.
Contrarian Corner.
This is your, oh, here we go.
We're back.
We're already down with you.
We're already massively on the order.
So I'm going to leave this here.
Actually, it looks good.
Actually, let me record it as well.
All right, we're in.
We are down.
Damn, are we down $5?
$6.
It is not looking good.
It's not looking good.
Flip up a fortune.
But we'll see.
We'll check back.
All right.
We got to see what happens.
We got to get towards 1 p.m. market close is where all the action happens.
So the money is made for the rich are minted and the price only goes up.
So we'll be fine.
That's true.
In the long term.
All right, Tyler.
Tear it up.
What are you going to tell us about?
All right.
Contrarian Corner.
So on the first episode, I gave probably my best contrarian take, which is that Bitcoin
might not do so well in an environment where AI takes off really fast and we get deflation
because that kind of kills some of like the value prop of the coins store value.
So that's still, I think, the choices take.
But if I had to choose another one to talk about right now, what I'm going to say is
I've been I've become kind of like black filled on the thought of self custody scaling to
like normal people, basically, because I think what you see over the course of the coin's
history and like crypto's history is that people are just not seeking that out unless
they have a reason to use it and people are like completely preferring to give up custody
of their funds to put them into vehicles like ETFs or micro strategy or whatever.
And I just am having trouble thinking of like what the killer app is for self custody for
Bitcoin or even for crypto at this point, because I think the thing that was driving
most people towards self custody and like Ethereum, for example, was essentially like
gambling or like DeFi and all this kind of like off of the yeah, investing 2.0.
Yeah.
And even that stuff, I think, like the case for it in the world, like that type of activity
has transferred onto like regulated like blessed platforms where people don't need to do it
like in the wild west of their MetaMask wallet and all that stuff.
Like if you want leverage and perps, you can get those through like Coinbase, Calchi, whatever
these days, all the prediction market stuff like that stuff is all completely blessed.
And so I think that was like one thing that people thought would be a killer app for self
custody.
It's not really panning out and I think in the Bitcoin world, like the killer app or
the reason to do self custody is just because you're like a good Bitcoiner, like you're
like I appreciate the values of Bitcoin and why it exists and like the fundamentals of
it.
I value like sovereignty, privacy, the freedom to move my own money, self custody, all that
stuff.
But I just don't think that that philosophy is scaling at all with the number of people
who are adopting Bitcoin.
Like basically the for each incremental wave of people that adopt it, lower and lower percentage
of those people like see the world in that way, it would make them receptive to thinking
that they should go through all the hoops of doing self custody and that kind of stuff.
Not to mention like there's a there's like a financial cost of self custody because you
have to pay for on chain fees.
You have to potentially buy hardware wallets or services to do it in a safe way and yeah.
So like I'm struggling a little bit these days to think of a use case for self custody
Bitcoin that isn't for like most people that isn't kind of like self-referential or just
like they'll just become Bitcoiners and then they'll understand the need for it.
I don't know, do you guys have any thoughts on that?
First off, I agree that most people are not going to become Bitcoiners.
But could you actually explain what self custody is for the viewers?
Okay.
One of the like driving principles of Bitcoin or other crypto assets is that if you interact
with the protocols directly, you do this by holding Bitcoin in a wallet and that's protected
by private keys and if you are running your own wallet software, then you can interact
with the Bitcoin protocol kind of directly and that means that there's no intermediaries.
It's just you and this distributed protocol.
And so there's nobody in between to tell you that you can or can't make that transaction.
There's no bank that sits between you and the transactions that you want to make that
kind of thing.
And there are a lot of benefits to that like you have say over where your transactions
get sent, nobody can take your money if they wanted to take it like there's situations
in a lot of countries where maybe the government will take funds from people or something like
that.
And if you have your funds self custody, nobody can take that from you if you do it correctly.
But yeah, that's like a potential amazing solution to problems that a lot of people
especially in like the United States like don't have right now.
And so it's potentially like hard to get them to think of the future where they might need
that and then to commit to this like, you know, rough kind of user experience and getting
their assets and there is kind of like insurance for a future that may or may not happen where
they will be glad that they did that.
So it sounds like what you were saying before is that like one of the features of self custody
is like a regulatory of what do you mean by that?
So like you were saying that like, you know, the self custody case, for example, for Ethereum
was like, you can do finance 2.0 and like, I think like, you know, a lot of finance 2.0
was facilitated by like the self custodial nature of the thing.
Yeah.
And like, you know, that's like a very salient thing, or was a very salient thing for people
when they didn't have access to things like perps in a regulated fashion, but like, well,
that was almost the proven grounds for all these financial products like that were done
in this kind of like quasi decentralized realm.
And then when they had clear product market fit and demand, and people knew that these
were things that consumers wanted companies basically just decided to take those concepts
and package them in ways that were like, totally centralized and then like lobby the government
to get like laws regulations passed that let them do that legally.
And then when you can do it legally, you don't necessarily need to do it on chain.
Like maybe that's the story of something like poly market, right?
Like poly market started out as this kind of decentralized friction market.
It still is, in some sense, and it's like built on polygon.
You can interact with poly market yourself using like the like root smart contracts and
stuff like that.
But my understanding is that basically almost nobody interacts with it in that way.
And that like a lot of the price discovery and the liquidity is coming to poly market
through essentially like centralized order of order books and points of contact and stuff
like that.
And so like, it's kind of evolved from this thing that was like decentralized because
it needed to be to now it's like, they took it and made it like a for profit company and
it's very centralized, but also it's becoming like legally blessed in the US and it's like
advertising all over the place.
Right.
And like, I mean, like the counterpoint there is, I guess, calcium where like that was always
a centralized product.
And it sounds like poly market is going towards calcium, not the other way around.
Yeah, that's my understanding of how it's working.
Yeah.
But yeah, I think I just am coming at this contrarian take from a space of like, I, in
the past worked on like self custody Bitcoin payments, and I love that space.
But we were always thinking like, who is our potential customer for these services that
we're building?
And I just don't think that there's like a huge market for that service as it is right
now like the maximally decentralized self custody payments kind of version of Bitcoin.
Are we up on the perps?
Yeah, we're up $1.
And like, I think that there's always going to be some, you know, minority of people who
like value that because they, they require that service.
And I think it's like amazing that that exists for those people.
Yeah, but I don't think like big businesses are going to be built on that and it's going
to scale to like millions of users, normally users who actually don't have those needs
as it is right now, unless there's like some huge big loss of trust or something like that.
But even you see in countries where there is like low trust, and people do expect to
get like rubbed by the government.
They're not turning to like the maximally decentralized self custody, Bitcoin assets,
they're turning to like assets that are rubbable, but like in a separate jurisdiction.
And so they like they don't trust their local jurisdiction, they put their trust in some
like corporation that exists in the US.
And yeah, I don't see that stopping anytime soon.
Because then the incentive for the corporation of the US is like not to rub those people
because they're very profitable, the incentive for the US is to let those companies keep
offering that service because they are creating demand for US Treasuries, which is great for
the US and they're extending dollar dominance.
So like everything about that system is kind of set up for it to perpetuate and grow itself.
And so it's like we're going to kind of be caught in this, I wouldn't even know if I'd
call it like a local maximum.
It's just like a, you know, some local stable equilibrium where like the people who are
in the countries that you might think or expect would care a lot about this self custody,
maximally decentralized thing, they're actually getting alternatives that are like, just,
you know, safe enough for them, and I trust enough for them.
And like, eventually that will probably, they'll probably, you know, there will be problems
with those systems for those people and they'll come around to thinking, okay, maybe I do
need that, like, more maximally centralized thing, but I think there will be like a longer
period in between where people don't think they need it.
And then if something happens, there'll be a lot of people like regretting that they
didn't use it, but you know, the damage will have been done.
It almost sounds like the longer you talk or think about it, the more you're trying to
come back to that self custody will happen at some point.
I wanted to.
Yeah, but I was talking about this with somebody recently too, and they were like, yeah, like
you could imagine that it just goes on for like, I don't know, like 100 years of like
high trust society, but then in 100 years, if something happens where there's like a
war or something, or there's like a regime, where then everyone suddenly values self custody
Bitcoin and then like, that's when it will be, it's time to shine, but it's like, if
it takes 100 years of people to like value that and then doing 100 years, people aren't
building the wallets, they're not working on the user experiences, they're not making
it like good.
And like that, those type of like muscles and stuff like that are going to atrophy because
there's no demand for it and the ensuing years and then by the time you need it, it will
be kind of like an afterthought, and that's a risk that happened to Bitcoin like becomes
this asset that you stick into ETF and you access through your brokerage account or your
micro strategy instead of actually something that you keep on a self custody wallet.
I didn't think we have 100 years, man.
No, totally.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying is like, I think the value and that's the thing or it's like,
I think part of the value prop of the whole network relies on there being like, maybe
not even a majority, but some like, you know, like a big chunk of people that actually do
have coins off of exchanges, etc, that do use it in a sovereign way.
And like if that share is just going to drift down over time as part of the adoption cycle
than like how, I don't know, is that like super pessimistic?
I mean, like, I think I like I read what you're saying that like Bitcoin is one of those things
where you don't know that you need it, that's what you do.
And then when you do need it, it's too late.
I'm like, I think like, you know, things are moving very quickly with AI, for example.
And I like, I don't know that that inflection point isn't like soon enough to like, start
pushing people more into self custody.
Why would AI is for people to move towards self custody, though?
I just think like the, you know, like, we're living in a very chaotic, chaotic era.
And I feel like the value proposition of Bitcoin is it is like, you know, this parallel rail
to the existing system, where like value can live and move separately to the existing rails
and like, as like, you know, like, we're looking at, like, my photos, just someone's quote
the RAM perps right now, which is like, as, as Claude said, has like moved, you know,
some insane amount in the past 10 days, like, as markets become more volatile, and the question
of like, how value is stored, and like, what value is and like, evolve, like, it seems
to me like there may be a place for Bitcoin in that world.
There may be, but I think the same cycle kind of plays out with the AIs too, or like, centralized
companies will build products to appeal to the AIs, you know, like, Coinbase is going
to build like an AI trading, you know, have your agent trade for you on Coinbase kind
of like experience, because that's what everyone is trying to build those kind of things right
now.
Because that's the future.
Yeah.
So I think that like this idea that like, like AI agents will be like shunned out of the financial
system because they're not people, I think that's like kind of fanciful, because all
of these companies have this extreme, like, incentive to try to be innovative there and
try to capture this new use case and this new like user service.
I don't think they're thinking about it as like, these are autonomous agents that can't
be trusted.
And like, we need to make sure we know who they are, like, they're just going to be like,
no, like, that's, you know, that's Jackson's agent, that he instructed to do a thing.
It's like his responsibility if he gave the agent the API key.
So like, you know, just deal with it, right, the hypothetically like pump liquidity into
the DRM market.
Yeah.
And then maybe just to switch gears a little bit, like part of the thinking on this also
is just like the like every cycle, you see that there's some kind of big incident where
you think like, well, this is going to be the lesson that finally teaches people like
the value of self custody.
And then every cycle, there comes like a new thing that's like a little bit different spin
on like the big rug pole or like the big custodial rug pole.
And like people don't learn and they do it and they kind of get caught in that honey
trap.
Like, you know, obviously it starts with like Mt. Gox, you know, that was the OG Bitcoin
exchange that people put their Bitcoin on and it was a custodian and the people who
kept their Bitcoin on there basically lost it because it got hacked and someone took
all the Bitcoin and then you have like a whole series of other exchange rug poles or hacks
as time goes on.
Probably the biggest one before this was just like all of the companies that went bust be
it like FTX or BlockFi or all those so it evolved from like, okay, don't trust exchange
with your coins to then okay, but like now the exchanges are offering yield like that's
almost too good to pass up.
And these people would raise venture capital and they would say like, you know, we have
like a risk management team from like, you know, Morgan Stanley, that's now helping us
do our risk management for our Bitcoin loans.
So like you can trust BlockFi and you can put your money with BlockFi.
A bunch of people put their money with BlockFi, it turned out that BlockFi was just lending
the money on secured out to three arrows capital and Sam Beckman freed and like they did no
diligence on those people, they just trusted them that the number would go up.
And so then you have that and then you think, okay, people would learn like all these people
who put their money on BlockFi and on FTX, those wet bust, like you got to self gusted
your coins, not your keys, not your coins.
And then this cycle, we get the new concept of like, okay, but instead of like a, you
know, like an exchange that gives you yield, what if it's like a corporation that you can
buy equity in and they like to use that equity to like leverage themselves and buy Bitcoin
and or create these like exotic financial instruments that are based on Bitcoin.
Like surely this is like the thing that's going to be safe because they're like corporations
and they're like good financial actors.
And yeah, I don't know where it goes from there.
I feel like this cycle we're going to see some of these, you know, corporate Bitcoin treasury
vehicles go completely belly up.
The model just won't work once they go below one net nav.
And then like next cycle, I look forward to whatever, like the next boss has to be like
governments, right?
Yeah.
Has like they went from like exchanges to now it's like corporations and then it's going
to be like, okay, now like the US government is offering you some like random Bitcoin, you
know, honey pot trap that people are going to like invest in and then it's going to get
roped.
Right.
When the US government is forced to not analyze part of MSTR, right?
Yeah.
And then, you know, as they have a higher amount of the underlying capital of Bitcoin by the
yeah, that will be it's just like the final boss.
Yeah.
The inevitable outcome.
100%.
Okay.
I think that's enough of my contrarian quarter.
I think unless you guys want to add to it or respond, I feel like I've just been ranting
for a little bit and like I don't want to get people down on Bitcoin or on self custody.
I'm a big proponent of self custody.
I do self custody for all of my Bitcoin holdings and I think it's the way to go for somebody
who's sophisticated enough to understand both the benefits and the risks and costs of it.
And that for me is the only way that I would want to interact with the Bitcoin protocol
and hold these assets, but I totally understand that other people have different, you know,
like utility functions around this stuff.
And I think that's part of my thing here is I used to think people would come around and
see things the way that I see them and value the same things that I would value.
And now I'm just like, I just don't believe that that's going to occur for other people.
So yeah, I think at some point self custody is going to become a really good product though.
Like I think like we're super like we're super early to it, right?
I think at some point it will become a really good product.
How are we super early?
It's been like 10 plus years.
Yeah.
But I mean, like, when was like the feed forward neural that invented like in the 80s at MIT,
dude, we could be talking about this in 2050.
I don't know.
Yeah.
But like Bitcoin is like a network too.
So it kind of edits an investment and so it requires other people like your, your experience
of it depends on other people adopting it in some sense, like kind of like a continual
influx of new capital or else your Bitcoin is going to be worthless if nobody else values
it.
I agree.
And like also the like viability of the network also depends on it not being like 100% captured
in a bunch of ETFs and stuff like that.
And then nobody is going to accept your Bitcoin for payment if all of this Bitcoin just sits
at coin based custody and it's just wrapped in ETFs and people are going to be like, what
do you want to pay me with Bitcoin?
Like this is an ETF asset.
Dude.
Yeah.
We need to go low.
I need to be like waking up in the morning crying.
That's like we need to shake some of these people out.
I'm with you.
I feel like you're implying that micro strategy is going to fail by the way, you're like comparing
it to FDX, comparing it to the Mt. Gox or whatever.
I don't think micro strategy is going to fail.
I think it's going to be a worse investment than just buying Bitcoin on its own because
it's encumbered in this capital structure and you basically are like using leverage.
And like what happens when you trade Bitcoin on leverage is that you feel great when it's
going up and that inevitably when things turn sideways and you don't time the market perfectly,
then you get an even worse pain than if you would just buy a spot.
And so yeah.
Are you shit talking leverage while we're $16 up on our 20X leverage around?
$16.
16.
All right.
We're 16%.
We used our money by 16%.
I know he's buying the burritos, actually that's on the floor.
It's on the perp of fortune.
Yeah.
Next episode will be agentic payments.
We're going to pay for a burrito with a perp of fortune.
Let's do it.
Geez.
Agentic payments.
What?
With stablecoins or with Bitcoin?
With this hyper liquid position, I guess.
Yeah, I can't even think of how we're going to make that happen, but we'll do it for the
pod.
But the next pod will be in Oakland.
There's not as many good burritos.
We happen to be in San Francisco right now in the mission district where burritos fly
sky high.
They put it on the trees here, man.
Exactly.
There is natural as oxygen in Earth's atmosphere.
So I don't know.
Maybe not burritos.
Pizza or something.
I did hear that DoorDash integrated tempo, so maybe there's something that, you know,
pick you back on that.
What a world.
What time to be alive.
What a time to be alive.
So a perfect example of a middle ground thing that took this concept of self custody and
crypto assets flying on blockchains, and then it's like, but what if we just made it essentially
an internal database and put assets on it that are controlled by the people who also
control the internal database, and then you just made payments with it.
Most people are, if that ever becomes successful, most people are going to be like, cool.
That sounds pretty similar to Visa, and I like Visa, but maybe it's cheaper, so I'll
go for that.
And that's a great FinTech product, but not necessarily the revolution that any of us
maybe wanted to see happen.
100%.
I think it's interesting how these platforms have this double layered approach where they
both own the platform and they are the synthetic version of every asset that is on the platform.
Yeah.
Very cool.
They're double dipping.
Yeah.
Not bad.
Do we want to pivot this into the stretch micro strategy discussion?
I thought that's where we were going.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll set it up.
So if you don't know what micro strategy is, micro strategy is a company that's traded
on the normal stock market, and in 2020, they were a very niche, random business intelligence
software company, and they came out of nowhere and said that they were going to buy Bitcoin
and hold Bitcoin as a company.
And people initially were like, huh, that's kind of cute.
What's going on here?
And they just kept buying more Bitcoin and making more noise, and then they developed
this whole thing where they started issuing debt.
And so they would go to the capital markets, and they would issue this secured debt, and
basically the bond markets would give them money, and they'd turn around and buy Bitcoin
with that money.
And so basically they're taking on leverage to go along Bitcoin as a company.
And this became the whole raison d'etre of micro strategy.
The whole reason of being is to buy Bitcoin with leverage.
And they did this for multiple years.
The chairman of micro strategy, Michael Saylor, became a famous guy on Bitcoin Twitter.
Very amenable.
He's very wacky.
He has a funky voice.
He makes music now.
Yeah.
He makes a lot of AI slop now.
He was in the Epstein files, and apparently Epstein thought that he was too creepy to hang
out with.
So that's the kind of dude he is.
Is that a good thing to be too creepy to hang out with Epstein or a bad thing?
I don't know.
Yeah.
I don't know how to read that.
I feel like it's probably a bad thing, but yeah.
Oh, no.
So micro strategy sponsored that.
Yeah.
So flash forward to 2026, and micro strategy owns 847,000 Bitcoin in their corporate holding
thing.
Yeah.
So they bought this Bitcoin for about $64 billion, and two-thirds of that $64 billion was funded
by them issuing equity.
So for a while, their stock was valued much higher than the value of the Bitcoin that
they held.
And so when that is the case, they issue stock because they can get a lot of money from just
issuing stock when it's overvalued, they take that and they buy more Bitcoin.
That increases the value of their Bitcoin per share.
So micro strategy, they bought all this Bitcoin, about two-thirds of it by issuing equity.
When their equity was valued way more than the value of the Bitcoin they held.
And then they bought the remaining one-third of it with debt.
And some of that debt is this kind of secure debt that I was talking about that actually
has these rights to convert it to micro strategy equity.
And then the other little bit of debt is something that they started doing recently, which are
what's called the preferreds.
And these are these really exotic financial instruments, one of which is Stretch that
they launched, I think, in the past year or so.
And basically, from what I can tell, the whole purpose of Stretch is like micro strategy
is extremely volatile.
And it basically trades in proportion with the Bitcoin price movements, but like amplify
because it has leverage.
Stretch, the idea is that it's like essentially like a stable coin on, you know, New York
Stock Exchange.
So the idea is that it trades at or around $100 per share, and it will stay there.
And then it pays the holders a dividend once a month.
And that dividend is basically a yield, and the rate is determined by and at the sole
discretion of micro strategy.
And so initially, I think the dividend rate was something like 9%.
And then basically, if Stretch is trading below 100, micro strategy raises the dividend
to make it, people want Stretch more and to demand more Stretch.
And they keep raising the dividend until it hits 100.
And then when it hits 100, they hold the dividend constant, and like that's their sweet spot.
And so they're trying to keep it at 100, but they actually have no obligation to do that.
So in the legal documents for the Stretch offering, it basically is like micro strategy
will like try to keep it at 100, but there's no guarantees or obligations that they will
keep it at 100, just kind of like vibes.
And what they can do is that they can take that yield that they say that they're going
to pay to try to target 100.
And they can just basically lower it at any point at their sole discretion, and they can
lower it as low as 4% perpetually for basically no reason.
And so for a while, Stretch was trading at about $100, which is great for micro strategy.
And when Stretch is trading at $100, they can basically issue more Stretch.
The market buys the Stretch, micro strategy takes that money that they get from selling
Stretch and they buy more Bitcoin, and that Bitcoin is owned by micro strategy.
The Stretch people have no claim on that Bitcoin, okay?
And so let's say two years ago, micro strategy was buying Bitcoin by issuing equity because
their equity was overvalued.
This year, micro strategy's equity is about properly valued compared to the Bitcoin they
own.
So they no longer have that leverage to buy more Bitcoin.
So they needed to cook up this new way to get money to buy Bitcoin.
And that's when Michael Saylor started talking to chat GPT, and he came up with Stretch.
So he's admitted that chat GPT helped him come up with the idea for Stretch.
And the whole purpose of Stretch is to raise more money so they can buy more Bitcoin because
they can't do it by issuing equity anymore.
So if micro strategy is this thing that's basically keeping the Bitcoin market, every
time they buy, it boosts the price of Bitcoin and it's this reflexive thing up.
When the price of Bitcoin goes up, people buy more micro strategy, it's overvalued.
They can issue stock, they can then use that proceeds to buy more Bitcoin, it keeps the
cycle going reflexively upwards.
It kind of has a little bit of a reflexive downwards loop as well.
And that's built into Stretch in a big way, because right now, Stretch has broken the
$100 peg hugely.
So today, Stretch is trading at about $75, which is a huge way down from like $100, right?
So if you bought this and you were like, this is like a stable savings vehicle, I expect
it to keep its value at $100.
And now it's down at $75, and you lost 25% of your savings.
You're like, what the heck, man?
I wasn't on board for this type of risk.
I mean, for context, we're saying that it's supposed to be a stable coin-like instrument.
The most historically catastrophic USDC peg when SVD went under, it hit 82 cents, right?
So 82 on the dollar.
Yeah.
That stretches at what now?
Like $70, $75?
That's right.
Yeah.
I would say there's two differences to that.
One is how fleeting was that D-PEG for USDC?
Hours.
Yes.
Okay.
Hours.
Stretch has been trading down for probably two weeks now.
Wow.
Yeah.
So it's broke the peg, and it's been kind of drifting down for much longer than hours.
And the second thing is that when people lost faith in USDC, that was because they were
thinking, okay, maybe the bank that the funds were held at went under, and that they might
have to go through FDIC to get their claim on the fund.
It was temporarily distressed, but I think people always believe that USDC was 100% fully
backed.
Stretch is basically backed by the hope that MicroStrategy will be able to keep paying
these dividends and this yield, and that they will raise the rate basically infinitely in
order to get the demand back up to 100.
Which they have no obligation to.
But they have no obligation to.
And if there's some limit to that, right, because if they ... Basically, everyone now
is observed.
If I bought Stretch at 100, and now it's trading at 75, this thing is not stable.
It's not a stable investment.
It's risky.
And I don't think there's any amount of additional yield that they can raise it to now that's
going to convince the average person that this is actually a stable thing that they should
invest in.
When I was at the Bitcoin conference earlier this year, they had ads for Stretch all over
the conference floor, and the ads were like a sexy girl in a bathing suit in the Caribbean,
and it was like, "I retired and put all of my savings into Stretch, and now I live off
my income in the Caribbean."
And it's like, that's who they're targeting.
They're trying to get you to think that you can have this free lunch where you can get
this cash flow without risking your premium.
And if you just saw your money go from 100 to 75, I don't know.
To me, there's no amount of extra yield that's going to convince me that even if they get
it back up to 100, that it's going to stay at 100 permanently.
And let's say that they have to raise the yield from ... I think it's at 11 right now.
If they raise it to something like 20% or something, I think they have enough cash on
hand to keep paying that yield.
But MicroStrategy has all of these preferred debts that have put options that come to be
active on them, and I think some of them start happening in September.
And that means that some of these debt holders, I think, can force MicroStrategy to buy back
a billion dollars of debt.
And that basically means that they would have to sell Bitcoin in order to do that.
So I think that they're going to have a choice, basically MicroStrategy, of like, do we continue
trying to play this stretch game?
And stretch is only $10 billion worth of notional for them.
And MicroStrategy owns $60 billion worth of Bitcoin.
And MicroStrategy has a fiduciary duty to MSDR shareholders, but I don't think they have
the same duty to stretch shareholders.
And basically, the only duties they have are the ones that they've laid out in the legal
document, which says that they can take the yield down to 4% at their sole discretion.
And so if it comes for them having to sacrifice stretch to protect MicroStrategy, or MicroStrategy
and Bitcoin to have to protect stretch, there's just no way they do that for stretch.
So to me, stretch is like this temporary blip in the matrix, where MicroStrategy was able
to basically acquire $10 billion more to buy Bitcoin with, and they found the right dupes
in the market that would give them that money in this really bad deal for them.
And they were just picking up pennies in front of the steamroller, and unfortunately, I think
the steamroller is about to run them over.
I think MicroStrategy is going to be forced to abandon stretch as a product, because it
will be too expensive for them to either raise the yield enough to restore confidence.
I don't think they can ever restore confidence now that it's de pegged down to 75.
And so I think their exit point is they can either buy stretch at distressed prices.
So they can buy stretch at 75 and basically set a floor for it.
But that's actually kind of expensive for them.
They have to buy back billions of dollars worth of stretch.
They have to sell Bitcoin to do that.
Selling Bitcoin is going to be bad for their equity.
They don't want to do that.
So what they're going to do with stretch instead is they're just going to abandon it, and they're
going to slowly lower the rate at the legally maximum rate that they can lower it until
it hits 4% yield.
And when stretch hits 4% yield, its value is going to be much less than it is today.
And so what you're seeing with the Deepak today, I think, is the market basically pricing
in the inevitability of them taking the yield down slowly from 11% to 4%, which is all that
they're legally mandated to do.
And then the terminal value of stretch will be something like, I don't know, like $30
to $50.
And it will pay 4% yield on that, and then 4% coupon on a $100 par asset, but when it's
actually trading at 30% to 40%, actually is a decent rate for those people.
But all the people who are holding stretch from $100 down to $30 to $50, that's going
to suck for them because they expected that to be essentially a stablecoin.
So when they say they pay 11% yield on the shares of stretch, if I bought, let's say,
one stretch for $100 and I get 11% yield according to the rules today, and it drops down to $75,
am I getting, is my yield still $11 a year, or is it now $8 a year?
I think the yield is defined on the $100 basis, but I'm not actually confident.
I know that exactly.
But I think that would make sense because their stated intention is to try to always
bring it back up to $100, so it wouldn't make sense for them to target it at some lower
value because in theory it should never be trading at 75%, so they shouldn't even contemplate
what the yield would be at 75% because that would render the whole product like toast.
So that means that if you buy it right now, you're actually getting 14% or 15% yield without
them having to adjust the yield?
Just like the matrimactic?
Yeah, based on the coupons that you're getting for the amount that you bought it at, yes,
I think so.
Is trading like a jump bond right now?
Yeah.
And if the percentage is returned on the actual price of stretch at the time the yield is
paid out, then you can think about how insane the flywheel of interest rate bumping would
have to be to bring the stretch back apart, right?
Yeah, totally.
And at a certain point, it's reflexively bad because A, if they keep raising the yield
at infinitum, they're going to have to come up with more and more money to pay the yield.
That means they have to sell Bitcoin, which means that they're going to damage microstrategy,
which means that they're damaging their own credibility, they're going to have to raise
the yield even more.
I don't think it will come to that.
But I think with a more likely thing is that it's just like, if they have to raise the
yield to 15% to 20% notional, that looks and quacks like a jump bond.
And I think that kills the vibe of stretches this essentially money market account that
just pays a better rate.
Yeah.
And I'm saying all of this as a person, I should have led with this.
I took a big chunk of my emergency fund, which is the money that you're supposed to keep
in like a savings account, money market account, whatever, last year, I took like half of my
savings fund, which is like, if I get fired from my job, that's you know, like three to
six months of expenses, I took about half of it and I put it into stretch when stretch
launched because I was like, dude, they're paying 9% like this is crazy, like, you know,
times are good, the coins trading at 100,000 like, you know, we're golden.
And the more research I did on it, I became super uncomfortable with that.
And so I ended up selling it all last fall.
And I actually made like a 1% to 2% like principal like game on on the stretch just based on
what I bought it at and when I sold it at and then I clipped a bunch of coupons in between.
So I actually did pretty well.
And I got like, it didn't wreck me like I, I came out on top.
But I came to a point where it was like, there's no way I can keep this money and stretch like
it's just like a shit coin.
So we've kind of like walked through the the history of micro strategy becoming this like,
I don't know.
It's like a hedge fund with like this elaborate capital structure.
So like a capital structure is basically how the company of micro strategy is constructed
and all the different securities that it has.
And you can think about it of like, if there's an issue with micro strategy, like who who
gets paid back first and there's like a waterfall of different classes of debt that gets paid
back first and then debt that gets paid back in a different way that has claims on different
assets.
And then at the bottom of that waterfall are micro strategy shareholders who basically
would be like the first to, you know, incur losses in some kind of catastrophic event,
but they're the ones that own the $800,000 of Bitcoin or the 800,000 Bitcoin.
It sounds like it's a hedge fund without hedging.
I think so, although I think from what I understand, they like did all of this debt and all these
secures.
Like if you think about the stretch thing I was talking about, it's like a really good
deal for micro strategy.
People are giving them $100 and micro strategy basically has almost no obligations to those
people with their hundred dollars.
So it's a great deal for micro strategy.
It's a bad deal for people who bought stretch and it's been that way from the start.
And it was just like they were able to obtain these like really good like legal agreements
all other debt and deals and stuff to structure and protect themselves.
And so I don't think micro strategy, the company, the equity is like doomed.
I don't think they're going to have to sell like all their Bitcoin.
I think they're going to have to abandon the preferred products at some point to save the
MSTR like golden goose and that then they will just be go back to being this like pot
of Bitcoin that is traded as an equity.
But I think also a lot of the like the shine of them that they had a couple of years ago
that led to them having this huge premium over their net asset value.
I think that will be gone.
And so I think that they will not be doing big Bitcoin buys so much in the future just
because I don't see them trading at a huge premium to their assets, which means they don't
have it.
They don't.
They can't like print the infinite money button anymore in the future, which I actually think
is like really good for Bitcoin because I don't think that Bitcoin as an asset should
become dependent on one mechanism for, you know, basically demand for the asset.
And it's like a very questionable source.
So like back to what I was saying, so we've gone through the history of micro strategy
becoming this like Bitcoin centered hedge fund or whatever.
What is what do you think is the end game?
What is what is next?
You're saying you think it ossifies at around 800,000 Bitcoin and micro strategy just sits
holding 4% of all Bitcoin that will ever exist.
And if so, like what impact does that have on Bitcoin as like a payment tool or, you
know, a new money?
I do think that's the end game is basically like they will run out of people who are willing
to give them money to buy Bitcoin with like they don't have they can't do it via the equities
anymore.
And I think they will not be able to do it via the preferreds anymore.
And so then it's like, if they if nobody is willing to give them money to buy Bitcoin,
then they're just a pot of Bitcoin that trades under a stock ticker, which is fine.
I mean, if they're if they're just valued like that, then they're just a de facto ETF.
Right.
That doesn't necessarily have become a spot ETF.
I don't think they become one, I think that they, you know, they are an effect one, and
maybe they continue to try to like maybe eventually somebody gives them debt financing again to
like do the leverage thing.
I don't know.
Maybe I wouldn't doubt sailor maybe you can cook up some new ways to like get money to
buy Bitcoin.
Sailor in chat GPT.
Yeah.
12am.
Do not fave them.
I've never done anything like that, by the way, if sailor gets access to fable, then
game on.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, I'm not going to be able to crack the kid of markets, but yeah, I don't think
that like the existence of micro strategy makes me any more or less bullish or bearish
on like Bitcoin is like a sovereign payments thing to me, that's like a whole separate
thing.
They have like 5% of the supply, like Bitcoin can, you know, withstand big, you know, corporations
holding them big ETFs holding them, but you need that like organic demand of people who
want to use it in a way to like make payments from a self custody wallet, older own keys,
all that stuff.
Like that's the thing that's going to determine the future.
They're not whatever, you know, sailor does with his pot of bitcoins.
And that's the stuff that I talked about earlier in my contrarian take where I'm like the demand
for using Bitcoin in that way, just I, I, I'm having a hard time seeing what like the
killer app is going to be that's going to get normal people using Bitcoin in that way,
even the current trajectories and all this stuff.
Do you not think that Bitcoin could succeed being transact or like using it for using
it custodially for custodially for payments?
Is it only succeed and self custody payments exists?
I mean, I think there's a lot of different definitions of succeed that that would be
the way that I wanted to succeed is I want it to be used for payments and to be used
for payments in a way that people can do self custody payments with like privacy and sovereignty.
And if they, you know, still like maybe a majority of people are doing custodial payments,
but then there's like the access of a not too small minority that want to use it that
way, then I think that's a pretty good outcome.
But like, I think there's other ways like, you know, Bitcoin could be successful as a
store of value if it kind of operates in this like, you know, captured way where most people
are just using it as a store of value and investing in it through the ETFs that isn't
my preferred way for it to succeed.
But that's like, I wouldn't say it's failed in that case, if it becomes like, you know,
gold 2.0, but like in ETFs and like maybe countries, you know, have their Bitcoin treasuries,
stuff like that.
It kind of makes sense for countries to have Bitcoin, right, if they're not the United
States, because we can kind of screw their international trade, since most international
trade is done in the US dollars, so like having Bitcoin as a country is like a hedge against
US sanctions.
Yeah, totally.
And if you are a country that has your own currency, usually you hold foreign exchange
reserves and different currencies to like stabilize your currency.
And it used to be like, unheard of that the US would like mess with other people's reserves.
But I think when Russia invaded Ukraine, the US just said like, all the treasuries that
Russia holds are now like invalid, like we just like don't believe in them, like, they're
like, you know, they just like basically took them to zero as a form of like economic warfare,
which I think was just like setting a precedent of like, okay, now countries don't believe
that they can hold US treasuries, if there's a chance that they are ever going to be in
an adversarial situation with the US.
So then what do they hold?
They need to hold like some kind of neutral asset that holds its value.
And I think for the most part, that's been gold, but you could imagine a world where
Bitcoin plays that role, I think has a long way to go before it does that.
Right.
I mean, like, gold has an enormous physical cost to keeping though, and like, it's very
hard to transmit.
So yeah, but if you're just using it to back your currency, yeah, like, it's just sitting
in a vault.
And you know, you know that you own it.
And yeah, you don't have to worry necessarily too much about transporting it all the time.
You would hope.
Yeah.
And like, I don't know, like the NSA can't just hack into your gold vault and steal your
gold.
Yeah.
I mean, you know, there are cold storage there egg gap solutions out there from what I've
heard.
Yeah.
Good point.
Yeah, it's like a fortress more secure than like a physical fortress more secure than the
digital one.
Yeah.
Versus like securing gold versus securing Bitcoin.
I think so right now, for sure.
Yeah.
I mean, if you're especially if you're a sovereign, like, you know, who's gonna like invade a
country and like go to their central bank and then like steal, like you basically just
have to do a full on ground invasion, that if that's your threat model, then like, yeah,
having your Bitcoin keys is not going to help you if your threat model is like the United
States ground invades you and like takes over your country.
They could.
And like, this this way, yeah, but George Clooney's coming back 70 years old.
One last go.
What, um, yeah, probably a bigger topic, but just like a last thing.
What do you think?
This has been a big one being podcast in case you guys don't know what, you know, it described
shortly what drives the Bitcoin price will each give an answer.
I mean, like, price just happens based on the supply versus the demand, right?
And so it's just kind of like who's the marginal person that wants to buy the coin that people
value it, is it being obtained for using to pay for stuff?
I feel slighted.
And I want to restate my question as what drives the man for Bitcoin?
I mean, I think the main thing that we've seen throughout history is that the Bitcoin
price going up in FOMO drives demand for Bitcoin.
Like there's no industrial use for Bitcoin.
So like Bitcoin demand is kind of self sustaining in that way, where like when the price is
going up, people get FOMO and they want to, you know, FOMO into it, but then that also
works on the downside, right?
But like, I could see there being arguments that like, there are exogenous shocks that
also increase the demand for Bitcoin.
Like one famous one is when Cyprus like forced all the people in their banks to take a big
haircut.
So like Cyprus was like a tax haven.
And I think like overnight, they're just like, okay, every dollar that you own in your bank
account is not worth like 60 cents.
And there was like this crazy rush of people to literally withdraw physical cash from their
bank account.
And then a bunch of them bought Bitcoin and the price of Bitcoin went up a lot during
that.
And then that also serves as a proof point of the value of Bitcoin and the properties
of Bitcoin for other people.
So you can see like, you know, little events like that, they're kind of like one time re-pricing
of like how people think about it.
But in general, I think it's just like the, you know, it's the, the price goes up.
People oh, what's up with this Bitcoin thing, they hear about it, etc.
And then like, just from a pure trading sense, it's just a game of bulls versus bears.
And you know, it's just your, your, your game of your, your, your perp of fortune.
10%.
Yeah.
You portion it.
You got to put more money in it.
I've talked enough on this podcast, I feel like I need to open the floor.
What makes Bitcoin price go up and down?
Yeah, I kind of agree with Kylo.
I think like this, obviously, like historically has been like a large speculative aspect to
it.
And I think that like at times where at least parts of like the traditional rails gum up
a little bit or like something occurs that like maybe, you know, creates like questionable
liquidity conditions for certain people, yeah, the price goes up, right?
Like I still think like it does have a place as like an asset of last resort or an asset
that like allows you to move value outside of systems that may have unfairly penalized
you or like where there's, you know, jurisdictional conflict, whether that's like court mandated
or like, you know, like more like sort of what's happening in UK, Ukraine, and Russia.
Yeah, I think like, yeah, I think that drives Bitcoin price movement.
And I think like if we do see more of that, like people looking for ways to move value
where like, you know, the fundamental trust game hasn't like, there's no trust.
There's no counterparty trust.
Like I think, I still think Bitcoin solves the problem of counterparty trust in some
of these, some of these places that like when that game, like the more trusted rails break
down, I think, yeah, Bitcoin price.
On that notion of trust, though, like if we're doing a transaction with Bitcoin, one side
of it is in Bitcoin, what's the other side of it?
And like, it's in some like physical like, I'm gonna, okay, I'm gonna send you like a
tanker full of oil and then you'll send me Bitcoin.
But then it's like, okay, do I give you the tanker of oil first or do you send me the
Bitcoin first?
Like, there's there's kind of like, there can't be trustless if it's used for real world
things in that way fully, right?
I completely agree with you.
But like, nobody, I can't give you the Bitcoin and then say like, Oh, that's not valid Bitcoin
anymore.
Yeah, at least like the movement, that leg of the movement is like, more so than like
if I give you like a USD bill, and I'm the US and then I'm like, I just have it all.
Yeah.
Like, you're bad.
You know, I understand like the technical aspect that acts like I can always kind of
send Bitcoin to whoever I want on chain, like, and you mentioned it being like an asset of
last resort, like I can send this, send this valley, you said send the valley when you've
been slighted by some financial system.
But like, what, what, what is the value that like, there must be some value for you to
be able to send it?
Yeah.
Does that make sense?
Sure.
I would say like, just this ironclad agreement that Michael Saylor is going to keep buying.
No, I know.
But like, yeah, I think Michael Saylor is propping up the Bitcoin price.
Yeah, I think like we all want there to be like some mono causal reason for things to
happen and the things to be worth things.
But I think like, you know, this like, like with every asset, there's like collective
belief.
That's true.
Yeah.
Actually drop a comment and say if you'd like us to deep dive, what drives the value goal?
Because I think that would be a good exercise for all three of us to learn.
I will get my answer as well.
What drives the price of Bitcoin?
I think that it's just speculation that you're going to make money.
And that's like, that's what you guys have.
We're just all hoping we make money off of it.
But I don't think that that is going to, that'll last forever.
So we need.
Whereas making money and like preserving your value again, you know, like one man's making
money is another man's preserving value.
If you live in a world where the money printer is going for preserving value.
Yeah.
Like you're losing money.
If you're like, if ever holding dollars and the inflation rate is 5%, then you're losing
5% of purchasing power every year.
But if you just put that money into Bitcoin and in theory, the supply of Bitcoin is fixed.
Like everyone else must do it too, right?
Yeah.
Or at least it should like, yeah, yeah.
I think that's the thing that was in the short term, but like that effect is so much dominated
just by like the animal spirits of the, like, you know, like the actual market psychology
of bull and bear cycles.
Yeah.
And, and we're also like, we're getting capital multi by DRAM right now.
Like all the spec with like, what is like by DRAM?
Yeah.
We're getting, we're getting screwed.
We're down to 6%.
Oh, that's bad news.
No, little burrito.
Yeah.
Small burrito.
I think it is time to go eat unless you guys have any other things you'd like to talk about.
We're going to get burritos.
Taqueria Cancun.
That's our place.
Yeah.
Any last thoughts for the fans?
I'm just like, yeah, I can't believe you did docs.
I said we're in San Francisco Mission.
I'll drop the spot after that.
You won't find us there.
You can't.
You can't get us.
Yeah.
Well, tune in next week.
It'll be our final pod with all three of us in person.
We're still figuring out the logistics, but we all fit on the couch.
So.
Yeah.
Nobody's laptoped up this week.
It's a milestone.
I know.
Yeah.
Let us know in the comments if you like the three of us in person or if you want one of
us to be a digital, a digital presence.
All right.
We're.