We will live another week at least as the government has yanked away
Fable five I want money now. I don't want money in 30 years. Who knows if we'll be around
Well, you got a roll of dice get out of the permanent underclass, right?
Okay, that's right. They won't they want their right to collect the rent, but not the obligation. It's not cheap house. Oh
Hello everybody and welcome to week two of the permanent under pod with Jackson cook Tyler
Chris Doran and Chris Doran today is June 18th. We'll try to get the pod out today
And yeah, you can see that now Chris is the man on the screen Chris. What's going on, dude? Why aren't you here?
so I'm in CDNX for a conference and by the way, I look this up before the
Underclass in Spanish is a soup class a permanent there. So
That's what I'm here for today. Excellent. Excellent. Are you a Spanish speaker? Like it looks like he went past maybe a high school level of Spanish
Uh, I would say I'm confident a high school level. Yeah, okay. Okay
High school like somebody in Mexican high school. We're like somebody in Australian high school
Australian high school. I could not claim. Okay, and Australian high school is like US elementary school level
Yeah, it's something like that. Maybe like kindergarten in terms of rigor. Yeah, I'm thinking more like
Comprehension. I don't know about the language mapping. But yeah
I'm kidding. We love our Australian friends. They're smarter than me for sure. Is there a lot?
Yeah, and our setting has also changed. We're in Tyler's house today. Look at this crazy window. Look at this couch
We've got a couch. We've got some trees outside. I live in the woods
Um, yeah
new location
I biked over here in this driveway and so see I thought like my chain was gonna bust
When I was going up it so I dismounted the bike
out of
safety
I think that your legs just aren't strong enough Jackson. If there's anything I've noticed from the podcast is that you have very weak legs
And they have a distinct lack of muscle definition
So I think that one's on you buddy. Okay bike shorts today. Yeah
I'm I'm pushing strollers up that driveway every day. I'm going down to get my mail. I'm putting my trash cans down there
It's like, you know survival the fittest out here in Oakland. All right
Yeah, well
Hills aside in locations
There's one elephant in the room or shall I say pee in the pod?
That we would like to we would like to address which is the production quality issues on the first episode
Most notably the video was smudged. That's because there was a smudge in my camera just fixed that before the pod
Number two, you may have noticed some audio. Yeah smudge smudge it up. Wait, don't use your finger though
Number two was the audio desync with the video
fixed that up and then number three
Was variance in the volume and I fixed that as well
for the viewers at home, um, this podcast is fully AI edited and
My skill for editing the podcast is open source. So if you're looking for the
Yeah, the permanent under pod editing AI skill hit me up because we live in a world where you don't have to thank anymore
Just throw it at the AI
And it was done by fable actually which is a sad story all on its end
I'm kind of imagining you like
When you were like, oh I need to take the smudge off of my webcam instead of just like taking a cloth and wiping it
You were like clog. Can you desmudge my webcam for me? And then clog was like, sorry Jackson. I
Am stuck in your terminal. I can't physically wipe your webcam and then you're like, ah damn I have to do it myself
I'm I'm luckily cognizant of physical limitations of my boy clod
Okay, and i'm i'm here to do his mechanical bidding
You're just clods meat robot. I mean, yeah
Yeah, I think fatal fatal for the fixing. I think fatal for the pictures
That's right. Yeah, fable would have ordered an agent take congress like
Human to come to my house and wipe it off
Like someone from fiber just like knocks up my door
Claude is here to send me to fix the audio desinking and the smudge like a 4.6 star podcast fixer
Well, i'm glad that you fixed our technical things where we're up in our game here, although, uh, you know chris in the
aero porto de siudad
Mexico
Um, we might get a little bit of background noise from some people who want to
Blow up our pod
Yeah, for sure. I'm expecting a cameo right here. Uh, so like let's wait for that
Did you buy a mariachi? What what is your experience been? Have you heard in any any like music while you've been there?
Yeah, I definitely have uh, you know, this is like a pod that sometimes you could peek over
That's our first guest
max besides besides pico which is
Um a lovely transition. We need our update. The fans are dying to know pico. Is pico. Okay
Pico is is well, he he has recovered almost fully. Um
He's sitting right here potting it up with us, you know honorary honorary pod captain right here chilling
and uh
Yeah, it was a saga i'll tell you that so we recorded this podcast number one on friday
And that was the day he got sick and he got really sick friday
And like we took him to the vet right after the pod for the record
We had an appointment. So I wasn't deferring his vet care until after we recorded a podcast. That's a level two
Too far Richard commitment because pico's welfare comes before the pod. I'm sorry to tell you that jackson
uh, but yeah, we take him to the vet and um,
so
my understanding of what happened is that pico wanted to go on a vision quest
And so he ate some poison mushrooms in our garden
But they were the wrong kind of poison mushrooms and they almost killed him
Wow, so he got he poisoned himself by eating mushrooms in our garden on thursday. It hits him on friday
He was like incapacitated
I had to carry him when we go to the vet they do all these tests and they're like, yeah
We think something's poisoning his liver. I was like, what the hell are you talking about?
And they're like you have mushrooms in your garden
And I was like, yeah
We do and we don't bother like picking them up because we all think that he's gonna eat them
He never wanted to eat them, but he's kind of acting out a little bit lately
So he was he was been eating these plums that grow in our garden
And I think he was like eating plum eating plum eating plum and he's like, what's this plum?
Adjacent thing on the ground. Let me try to eat that he ate a poison mushroom
so
He basically was like pretty messed up for three to four days
We had him on a bunch of medication got a little dicey a few moments. We took him back to vet
uh, but now he's
He's healthy. He's gonna pull through it and I think he has some new life perspective both from the effects of the mushroom the plant teacher
and uh
Also from his near death experience
But now we it kind of sucks because I don't want to ever let him
Out in our yard or garden like off the leash. So now it's like what I just have to like
Put you on a leash and like take you out when you want to go pee all the time like that
That's no good. So we'll have to figure out what to do with this boy
number one howls for pico
Let's go my dog
Well an alternative is you can just clean up the mushroom in the garden perhaps
Yeah, that's gonna be the plan but so right now it's like the mushrooms they sprout in the spring after like it rains
Or it stops right? I forget what it is
But there's one moment where they all appear and then you can grab them then because they're just there
But if you don't grab them, then they kind of like fall off the stem and they just start like decomposing on the ground
So they're kind of hard to find now because they're like mixed up in a bunch of like leaves and decomposing stuff
And if you're a dog, you can find them with your nose and then eat them and almost die
Uh, but i'm not gonna crawl around my garden looking for those probably with like a fine-toothed comb. That's just impossible. So
Next mushroom season we're going harvesting. Maybe pico's a bit Italian, you know, like a bit of a truffle hound
It seems like he has a good instinct for it
So we should try to train him to detect truffle smell in the past. Maybe that was uh the issue
Yeah
So like when he was a puppy
We lived in like that small apartment in the mission and we didn't have enough stuff to do with them
And so we would like dab truffle oil on like a can of soda or something
And then we'd like hide it
In one of three boxes and we'd like do the old rearranging them and take them out of the room
And then bring them back in and tell them to find the trouble
uh, and so you got kind of good at that and so maybe maybe this is like the
You know tragic moment in pico's character arc where everything went wrong when I was teaching them to find troubles
And I was just you know, that's like the check out gun on the on the wall of our play
Leading up to the tragedy in act three, which is him eating these mushrooms
But uh, no, i'm really happy that he is gonna do well
He's still uh, like pooping blood which is not very fun for him. I would imagine
That's like the only thing that's still kind of like you can notice but otherwise he's like
Going on big walks. He's annoying me because he wants more exercise
Uh, he's back to his old friendly self. So that's the pico update. That was a long segment
But I think that's what the listeners are here for. So I kind of wanted to like really belabor it
Yeah, just like in movies the dog dies. It's tragic for some reason, but if a human dies, it's whatever
We're happy pico's. Okay, we're not losing any viewers over this one. Hopefully one of the co-host doesn't die by that reasoning
Let's be honest if I wasn't here like it would be okay
But if either wasn't here like we did
No, wait, man, we we need you you got a lead in the in the segments upcoming
Yeah, you're a technical expert on all the things that are actually here and jax and I are just here to bullshit
Yeah, yeah speaking of bullshitting we also owe you guys an update on the lottery tickets
So we put a total of 15 or sorry. I put a total of 15 dollars in on three lottery tickets
walked away with eleven dollars
The dude at the corner store was a gas that I did not use that eleven dollars to buy more lottery tickets
You took the money off the table, man. It's very financially irresponsible. Yeah, he's like you really want cash and i'm like dude
Yeah, i'm done with this
Also, I got ripped off you guys know I got the loteria like
I can't remember the name of my spanish
Lottery ticket for five bucks and like downtown oakland. It was three bucks at this corner store
So wait, so they just charge an extra two dollars on top of the lottery ticket. Yeah, man
Is that like sanctioned or did they literally just see you walk in and they were like this guy has no idea
Like let's just steal two dollars from him. It was the sticker on the lottery
So it's like they didn't swipe out the sticker when I was rolling in
Oh
That's like uh, that's their setup for the the naive lottery player. I think
Yeah, I can't say sorry
You don't know they call the uh korean big point of like the kimchi of the kimchi premium
Like we have an impetus the lottery ticket mexican lottery ticket premium
Uh, I don't know the the salsa
premium
The contact yeah
Yeah
Yeah, what is what is is kimchi is like peria's?
National food. What is mexico's national food is it must be the taco?
well kimchi is like a
It's like a condiment almost that you eat with like all the foods, right?
And it's like on the tables. I don't know as a as our korean expert. I think you should be opining on this
Yeah, I wouldn't call it a condiment
It's a side dish. Okay in custom area when you're eating as a korean to have many side dishes
That are often a mixture of cold lukewarm and warm. So
It's different than a condiment where condiments are kind of
Mostly served with warm and or saucy in nature
That is to say if you say kimchi is a condiment
Then I see why you thought salsa would be the salsa discount or salsa premium. Yeah, but i'm gonna say the national food
of mexico is probably the taco but
I don't know. Don't cancel me before i'm not the mexican expert. I think right now that's chris
So you can go to mexican experts
Uh chris tell us about this conference man. Give us the highlights compare it to maybe some of your past
Conference experiences in the crypto world
Sure. So I am in
CDMX in mexico, um for the latin stablecoin conference
Uh, and uh, yeah super super interesting. Uh, I mean like I think there are a lot of tailwinds here as we all know
Uh, that's the only that the genius act is getting closer to being negotiated
uh
So there's like a lot of uh tailwinds for obviously like stablecoins and stick phones in latin
um, but uh, you know, like i'm i'm from the chain, you know, i'm from the mean streets of the memorable and uh
uh
Let's just say that like institution's idea, right? Like uh,
Uh, it's not I don't think like, you know, there's no jp morgan chase booth, but uh, I think conceivably they could be
next year
um, it definitely like it felt like the industry is
Changing and I think like if it came salient to me for maybe the first time ever that's like
uh, you know, um
Maybe our quest to just intermediate middlemen has potentially created women and men
Are we the baddies now?
All right. I mean not us but are are the are we the baddies now, you know
Yeah, like I had a moment like where I looked in the mirror and I was like, who am I?
um
But uh, I think you know, it's very nice in space and it remains to be seen
How this settles but I think people are very interested
Yeah, that's my boy. What's like the attire like you said it's kind of fancier or were you underdressed?
Or what's going on?
I was massively underdressed like, you know me i'm like a t-shirt jeans
Torn-up hat spectacles guy. Um
And uh, it was all it was all chinos and uh, and button downs
So, you know
I was shocked. I was shocked. So for the context my
Probably like the last big conflict I went to was death on
Thailand in 2024, which is for anyone who doesn't know it's like the big the hearing one. They do every couple of years
uh, and like
Everybody was like dressing like they all they were just like leaves. Uh, it was great
Did you get on stage and do like a unicorn dance with metallic during that's like a tradition, right?
As everyone's awkwardly dances on stage and then it's like fodder for crypto twitter for the next couple of years
And it causes like many years of ethereum bear market because the vibes are so putrid
Yeah, I I created a video of it when it happened. I was like i'm selling my
If I had, uh, I would be a Muslim musician
Something to figure out that was the top
unicorn dance
Speaking of uh, jakey morgan and stable cloyans
Have you seen that like jamie diamond is on like a personal vendetta against brian armstrong about the genius act?
And he's like he gives like interviews on cnbc and he's like brian armstrong is full of shit
That guy is a fucking bullshitter like he's like
Goes after armstrong and his whole thing is basically just that like
armstrong is trying to buy
Uh using lobbyists and like a lot of donations the administration
This like super favorable legislation for him specifically and it basically lets
A company like coinbase kind of like operate in the banking sector
Doing banking type functions, but with none of like the requirements that a real bank has
And so obviously diamond is pissed off because he's like you can't have
This guy doing all the same shit over there with no regulations and then have me held to this other standard for like
Capital controls and like aml and oakback and all that stuff
And so I don't know that makes me kind of bearish on genius because like I just imagine that like jp morgan
the coinbase like
Probably jp morgan wins that in like the war of you know, like washington dc dollars
And also, I think he's like honestly probably right like I think the genius act is probably
uh
Not concordant with like prior banking policy
And if there's anything that I like about it, it would be that like, okay
Well, then the prime prior banking policy is like too
overregulated
And then like but then you need to maybe
Apply that philosophy to like all institutions that conduct that type of activity
Not just carve out this special little handout for stablecoins and coinbase. That's like super to me just like rent seeking behavior
And yeah, it is like one rent seeker trying to replace another rent seeker. So like i'm not going to cry too many tears, but like
Um, that's kind of my feeling on on genius in general as it just doesn't interest me. Um
I I tend to agree with you tyler and one sentiment that i've uh bandied around in the ground is that like
You know like sort of how is this going to work, right?
Like you have these like incumbents who you know have gone through the hard yards of getting the regulation
And they proceed to themselves to have done the work
Uh, and then and then others trying to come into this space
You know, like you're saying like looking special carve outs or like operating these great areas
Like I think there's a lot of pressure
To either like, you know regulate the new players correctly or or just push them out as in with any competitive budget
So yeah, I agree. It's not clear to me
Exactly what's going to happen here, but I think it would be exciting
Yeah
Sorry, I just have a question. I don't know what rent seeking means. What does what does that mean rent seeking behavior?
um
Yeah, it's like uh
in this case
It's like a company that finds some kind of way that they can like systematically kind of extract
Like a fee or like some kind of value out of something and they're not really producing value themselves
It kind of just flows from like them having some position
uh
yeah, and so I don't know I guess in that context i'm kind of uh suggesting that like
A lot of the profits that banks make are kind of protected because of the regulatory regime that makes it so there's like
Two or three big banks that exist and therefore like they kind of own this market in an old outlook like sense
um, and then yeah, like if coinbase is trying to become the new version of that they're trying to extract rat rents by
Having their stable coin be like banking 2.0
And they make money on taking the interest on the treasury bills that back it and then also they charge fees on an off-ramp to it
um
I don't know chris. Do you have anything that you would add to that like?
uh
Yeah, like I think in general it's just like it it might be like something that you do when you have kind of like a monopoly
Or you can abuse your market position and to like charge more than you should otherwise and especially when it's protected by
Some kind of like regulatory capture or something like that
Yeah, I would work. I mean what I would my ad and I think I can only get spicy because oh and
Like we've already mentioned this ourselves. So that's a lot of thing
um, everybody that i'm seeing is trying to cut and paste that exact same formula that you're describing pilot that like
You know either current stable coins are doing or previous banks have done
Whether trying to centralize liquidity on that platform or centralize operations on that platform
And develop as many partnerships as possible and basically, you know, force people through another jp nordic
Situation and then you have to directly with the institutions and thereby they set up a toll booth to extract rent
Uh, so I mean but but those are most of the strategies i've seen
Recently probably in the past six months, uh, but like that it's not it's not clear to me that that really want to know
But yeah, just just my books
so
It's rent seeking behavior
brian armstrong the ceo coinbase to be lobbying to basically be banking to point out
But is why isn't it rent seeking behavior or I guess it's so it's just like it's not they're not seeking it
But they've already acquired the rent for the bank, but it's like the same. They just want it
brian armstrong wants the benefits that they have
Or have but without any of the burdens that they have I think is kind of a new
Uh, like the new wrinkle on it
Okay
Okay, that's right. They want they want their right to collect the rent, but not the obligation
Ooh
That's that's a sick. Um
That's getting that plot is flipping that
Yeah
That one's a one minute zinger short
Let's see. Let's see. Let's see
We shall move on to another topic. I think unless you guys have more on that
No, I appreciate the rundown
Boots on the ground report of the stable plan conference
Did you personally like make any handshake deals?
You know, are we like?
You know we're yeah
I guess you can skip that one. But uh, we'll just cut that segment because that's a little bit too
These hands on the desk at all times, you know, yeah, yeah and they're very like, uh,
You know, I try to stay trustworthy
Can I ask actually did you make any stable coin payments while you were in mexico?
Could you could you buy any tacos with stable coins? Did you seek out anything like that?
That's a great question, tyler. I did I tried to
Uh, and it didn't work and let me tell you what
Uh, so it was a qr code scan and in the devian ecosystem instead of qr code
There are like some options for what they show you right? But sometimes it'll just be the address
Uh, sometimes it'll be a different type of uh, you are right. Uh, one of them is called vip 681
I know that's enough with but basically it can encode the token that you're sending
I mean it helps and so this one was an ei eip 681 screen
And my wallet couldn't read it and I couldn't pay uh, and I think you know
My head wanted me to download the title of it. I don't know what I'm gonna do
So yeah, it was an epic failure
Interesting you said e
evm and eip
What are those two acronyms?
so evm means ethereum virtual machine, which is the
Sort of compute layer that a lot of chains from it has like consistent addressing standards
various things that you can depend on doing the chain
uh, and eip stands for ethereum improvement protocol and it's just how
Uh, beliefs like us label certain features. So in this case, it's a an addressing point
I see it's like bit
But exactly which is bitcoin improvement
You could say it was played your eyes probably I wouldn't but you could
Okay, actually this makes me want to ask more questions like
Do you think that consumers will
pay in
Stable coins either of you think consumers will pay in stable coins. Like is that
a potential future
I do
but I think
It's running into the exact cooperation problems that blockchain was meant to solve right and like what are they?
Like what is the standard of payment right like who owns?
The you know, it's basically the funding rate of the payment. So like who owns the state of money
How do they interoperate with each other, right?
And it seems like banks led to their own devices kind of had a real trouble
Agreeing on terms to solve these cooperation problems and I feel like you know, one of the problems is crypto
Was that it's a mutual ground where everyone can cooperate but you know
I think we're seeing in the stable point realm like this start to sort of statement and falconize a bit again
And it's not again. It's not clear to me
These corporations will be able to come to terms again in a way that actually benefits
So i'm not sure so chris. I have uh, I have thoughts on that, but I tend to think about it as like
Like us versus non-us
So for us, I don't really see stable coin payments taking off because like everyone here has great access to dollar rails already
That works super well and like there's just like a big incumbent ecosystem where like
You know, there's just a lot of inertia there
uh, and I think
Maybe where I can see stable coin payments being more and i'm talking about payments for real goods and service
Not like cross-border p2p. I can maybe see that use case for us
Stable coins, but for international stable coin, I could see payments for goods and services being a little bit more
realistic in the near term
Especially in countries where people have a revealed preference to save in dollars over the local currency
Because then it's just like a very quick
It's like a natural bridge from like I save in dollars because that holds value better
And then like why wouldn't I spend in dollars if I can spend from my saving because then I don't have to convert into local currency
So do you think that's like a
Worthwhile synthesis you think it breaks along those lines?
Or do you think that there's more potential for stable coin payments in the u.s than i'm giving a credit for?
No, I tend to agree with you completely. I think it like
I like I agree with your thesis. I think it like puts
I mean, you know both these governments and companies in an awkward position in terms of like which stable forms we accept
Like how how do we get this like, you know kind of sale
Situation working directly these bullets working correctly with each other
But also uh, then like for governments like a substantial amount of your population essentially is holding us off and dead
Uh and your sovereign debt, you know, no longer has about to apply. So I I don't know how that plays out
I don't know what happens here, but I think we're very interested
Yeah, well you saw it like um, the government of nigeria did to like finance basically
Like they they had a huge inflation in their currency people in nigeria were going to try to hold tether
And they are getting tether on finance
And then like the government of nigeria like held
Specific individuals that worked at finance liable for this and like arrested them even if they like
Wears like some random. I think the example was like a guy who
Was a u.s. Citizen and he worked like on the compliance department for finance and he visited nigeria
Not even in an official capacity and they like arrested him through him in jail like in really horrible circumstances for a long time
So like that's an example of it gone really bad
When the government is not happy with this kind of spontaneous dollarization via crypto reels
Um, but yeah, the interesting thing there is like they couldn't actually stop it to my knowledge
Like they did make an example of this one guy, but like I don't know if that
Meant that finance left nigeria
I don't know if that means that people in nigeria use stable coins any less than they previously did my guess is no because the
Incentive for them is so strong when their local currency is inflating so hard
so like it will be very interesting to see like
governments kind of like fight it until they like realize it's maybe um
Kind of like a lost cause and then they embrace like full dollarization
um, and I think you probably see like a waterfall of that and obviously it starts in the currencies where you have the
highest inflation the highest historical inflation the highest like historical preference for the dollar and just making that so much easier
And like in some cases if it's done self-customy wise, you know
There it's actually like much more decentralized and there isn't necessarily a local locus of control
um
so
Yeah, that would be interesting thing to see play out, but I can't imagine that most
governments would be happy to see their local currencies be
um
Like organically replaced by spontaneous dollarization because that would be a really
Tough transition and it would leave a lot of people
As kind of losers, honestly like the way the doctors um, and then it's yeah, that's no good
And it makes the government less powerful. The government is a huge loser because they lose the power of the money printer
I think yeah
Then that's like exactly what you're seeing in stronger countries with some stronger currencies and stronger economies such as korea
Where they're racing to pass these
They're racing to pass these stable coin
Uh legislation because they don't want their
um
Constituents are like people that live in the country to start using the the u.s dollar
And it'll be interesting to see how it plays out like and what regulations countries put on
uh
Citizens using u.s. Dollar. Well korea already has like a very
restricted like capital account and like
Flows, right? That's the reason the whole the whole reason the kimchi premium exists is because it's like hard to um
I don't know like trade across
One like get one out of the country to then convert to dollars to buy bitcoin to the senate to the country to sell
for one right so like
They seem to be already pretty good at financial repression in that way
And so I guess they already have like their system on lock
um
But yeah, it's not the the worst example of that in the world. So the people are probably generally
Not it's not hyper inflating in the same way that other countries are but they're still like repressed in the sense that they
They don't have that access as easy because the country historically has those restrictions really on lock
One thing I would like to add is I met some people who were tokenizing non-u.s
So my dad and one of their bigger clients was korea. Uh, so that's recognizing, you know, like korea
Saltman dad's been a lady born on chain
So I think like it seems to me like from the outside like very naively that uh, you know
The korean documentary is once or like that, you know, there are elements in korea that are quite like amenable
to like pushing this
How do you like even price the sovereign debt of a country that has like a
1.0 birth rate
You're like they're gonna pay this bond back in 30 years when they have like, you know
40 of the population they do today or something
That's crazy
Everybody's looking for a much more bio. That's that's what i'm that's what i'm seeing. Yeah
Wait, you said you said that they're tokenizing non-sovereign debt, right? What does that mean? No sovereign
So it's like uh, the korean budget of t-bills was my understanding. I see
Okay. Yeah, I don't know what the
what the repayment of
T-bills or whatever
What it happens if you die
I could be totally wrong. Yeah, at least somebody looked up what korean t-bills returned, but I understood it was like 2 percent
So I don't know that's I think that could be
a tough sell
but we'll see
Maybe first first to market or whatever and less regulation could help them
But that's a very low rate like wouldn't
My understanding is that like basically everyone pays a higher rate than the u.s
Because the u.s is like the gold standard and the u.s t-bills pay like three or four percent right now, right?
So i'd assume there's some premium for them to the u.s
So they'd be above that but I think it's like the u.s is the gold standard and maybe like
I don't know like switzerland or somebody like crazy like that
Maybe pays a little bit less than that, but um
Could be wrong
Gemini is telling me these money stabilization bonds. What's going to be five percent. I'm not i'm not an oh, okay
They must be superior to exotic money stabilization thing
2.5 percent. That's pretty. Yeah, I mean, but you could just be getting 11 percent in stretch
So why would you ever mess with these money stabilization bonds the bitcoin guy?
No
Stretches, you know, why not? Do you not buy stretch? This is not financial advice. Don't buy stretch
Can we say that at the start of every podcast, please?
I just I think we need to get that out
Yeah
I think I need to throw out the disclaimer too
That are the things we say on this podcast are our own opinions and they're not affiliated with any
Any of our employers whether or not we work at one company here or not
Are I would say some of these things are even barely my opinion right so like let's start that
Good
Okay. Well
I think it is time time for you to shine chris
We're going to move into the meatiest topic of the day, which is
Perks
Not to be confused with perks
Which we also like but perks perpetual futures chris is our resident
perp expert
So chris please take it away. Tell us what perps are tell us why they're popping off
Tell us what the latest is on regulation. Give us it all
Uh, all right
So i'm gonna do my best here, uh for context
Thanks for like, uh, talking about but i'm i'm mostly more of a spot guy
Uh, but I guess i'm like, you know the happiest guy on the podcast. So i'm gonna do my best
Before you start one sec. You maybe you should record on your phone or on your laptop the audio just in case
Just in case because sometimes when people talk in the background
It's a little hard to hear you and i'm scared the ai won't be able to edit that well
This is keeping in the pod. Just a shout out. We're thinking of you viewers
All right, sorry go ahead chris I didn't mean to interrupt you below you were popping off
Oh good i'm recording now, uh, so, uh, you can think of a perp as like, uh a future so the
uh, you know one of the traditional american style features is like an american style full option where you have the option to buy something
At a certain price at a certain time in the future
so like, you know one way to think about this is
As you trend towards the time in a future that you've bought the option for the price of that call should
Tread towards the actual price that it will be in that line, right?
So you have a backstop, you know
But you know what the price of the call will be
But you know that the price of the call will be the price of the asset at the time
That the call expires, right?
so
Uh, you know, these are like quite hard to reason about and I think like a you know a famously
In this unit's financial instrument
um
So, you know, let's get into perps which are like an even more difficult to reason about you know more misused financial instruments
So you can you can imagine a call, but there's no expiry
So that you know one function of the call is
All expiry, you know, as we're saying is to bring the price of the call to the price of the underlying spot
with a perp
instead of there being uh
You know a time when it expires and you have to execute like exercise your option to buy
You have this thing called a funding rate, right?
And a funding rate is just saying
You know whether longs pay shorts or shorts pay longs and the intention of the funding rate is to do the same thing
It's to to bring the price of the perpetual future
closer to the price of the underlying spot
Uh, and in that way you can uh run it up on leverage using the synthetic asset
Uh, basically for a time of year. Um, so so practically the way it works for me
uh, you know as we fail is I
all the way I interact with bugs is I I go to
A venue and I won't name any um, and I say I want to
You know long bitcoin. Are you not naming any because you're holding out for our future sponsors?
Yes
Uh, yeah, I I try to bring this to the table. Yeah
Hyper liquid, uh
We're we're we're really what are you doing?
We don't want to close doors if there's like I don't know less hyper liquid or anything
Yeah, we'll take any sponsor. Sorry
Oh now we have to say all of them
Okay, say them all
uh, I I want to know that um
so
uh
Yeah, uh, where was I?
Uh, so okay. So the way I interact with the purpose retail like under exchange and I say I want to like 100x long
Asset let's say big point which is the traditional one
Uh, and I will put 100x into the slider
uh, and my notional will be
You know 1% of the value. Sorry about my what I put down will be 1% of the value
Right, so I you know
put down zero point
0.01 bitcoin, uh, and i'm exposed to you know a hundred times the profit or loss of that bitcoin
But i'll get liquidated
If it moves too far in the range
Uh, so yeah, it's a very like it's a very risky
loss of financial asset
Um, I think like a lot of people have made it famous with these like insane blowups, right?
where they put in like a hundred x platform and it just goes up but like
Uh, I think many more people, you know will put in these risky
Uh, potentially futures and get liquidated and uh, basically that thing
So why do we need these if not, is it just the answer to scrambling?
Like is there any like you like, you know in traditional futures
They're like well, you know, like the farmers need to like hedge their crops or the airlines need to hedge their fuel costs
but like
Is is there any redeeming factor to a perp other than it just lets you like express a very?
Leveraged financial debt and like it never actually settles to the physical the underlying
I yeah, I really I really you know, it's in some sense. It's a synthetic version of the underlying
It's like the collateral you put down is not
In the underlying right it could be anything
uh, so yeah, I I don't know that there is a great argument for it except maybe as
Kind of like a money building block where you can impose a curve as a primitive something else
so like one that you mentioned last podcast pilot is um
In usd or at vino, uh, and they use
A delta hedge position to create a state
I mean it's interesting, right?
but but at the end of the day like
The underlying primitive it seems to be
Uh, basically just for blowing it up crazy. So
That's my understanding. I'm
I mean, maybe you can make an argument that like it's an expression of a free market and so it helps
with price discovery because it lets people express like
their um
thesis like even more
Granular and richer with like yeah the structure
But uh in reality, I feel like it's mostly the latter and I feel like um
Purps were invented by bitmex. Right? So this was like a crypto native
invention of how to do these
was there um
Is part of the reason that bitmex invented them was because they were like a fully crypto native exchange
Because I think when you did bitmex you like deposited bitcoin
There was like no stable coins at first
And so your collateral was bitcoin and you need to trade this bitcoin
Like was that the reason why or am I over complicating this? Did they just want to invent something that like?
was
Simple for retail traders to like take big bets on
Uh, yeah, so I mean I was close friends with a guy who I could bitmex for some time
But think this would be a very great assault. Yeah, my understanding is that yes, you know, that is the case
So bitmex would just accept bitcoin
Um, and you know famously they did not check who they were accepting bitcoin from
Uh, but you know once you have that bitcoin collateral
Um, maybe you want price exposure to other assets, right?
And it's a way to do that is with potential this right
Where you can have your collateral be one thing and you're exposed to the other
Um, so I think in that way bitmex went in very successfully. Wait, did they have
perps on other
Like did they do perps on other things other than bitcoin? I thought it was literally just only bitcoin trading on bitmex
I believe it originally was just bitcoin's rating. Yeah, I think they often on the perps later down the line
I don't know exactly. Okay, was that after their heyday though? Like I feel like they were like
Killing it in like, I don't know
2015 to 17 they were like the premier price discovery blaze for bitcoin
And then I think binance like stole all their thunder because binance maybe was offering just like way more
altcoins and stuff like that
um, and then they've kind of just like
Existed since then but I don't know if they're like thriving and then you know ftx almost stole binance's thunder
But then they blew up
And they had their own spin
On perps, I think I don't know if it was their own spin
But they they're big thing was they had this like different
Risk engine for deciding when you get liquidated and they said that was their competitive advantage
For sure my feeling my understanding that bitmex's risk engine was famously maligned
um, yeah, so they like
You know that whole engine was running on this, uh stream of performance that did all the finance years for a database called booby plus
Uh, and you know from the outside, uh, I don't know. I just I see what explains about it
No, they they have to like build up an insurance fund because like they need a pot of money
So that they can pay people out when they like failed to liquidate people correctly
And so they'd have like they they mess up the liquidation somehow
And then they'd have like a deficit of money
And so they would need to pay that out from some fund that was basically just a tax on all transactions or something
I feel like so socializing the loss. Yeah. Yeah, yeah
Um, and I think you know, I think like most participants are not that bad, right? Like, uh, if uh, you know
You've run through much to where there's no
Uh, sell side liquidity, uh, that you know, they they start closing
Positions on the other side to socialize the losses after they run through
Being sure that's my understanding
Is that just happened because there's nobody available to like take on that additional
Risk, like there's that funding rate and like let's say like wouldn't the funding rate just change?
so dramatically to incentivize somebody to come out of the market and like
Come like rejoin the market and kind of fix that dislocation
Yeah, so I I again like i have another another one next but my understanding is that on this podcast you are an expert
All right
Sorry, you're the expert on this podcast. No, no more disclaimers
Yeah, yeah, I gotta do my best. Uh, so when the price price diverged too much from the underlying spot price, right?
There's an arbitrage possible. Yeah, so so say the price trading at 102 and the underlying is trading at 100
There's like a two grand arbitrage there where a market maker can buy the short position to fill someone else's long
Uh, and then immediately hedge it by buying spot at 100 grand and pop it 2k plus the money
um, but if
If the divergence isn't there or like, you know, it looks like they don't want to be on the long side of the freight train
Uh, that's like where the price is running up
You know, maybe market makers want to come to the table. This is too much risk
So it's not enough juice in the trade
And hypothetically your funding rate should come in and correct that but it doesn't always sometimes things move too fast
and I think that's where you get these
Force liquidations with people in good positions to to even up the book
um for different solutions
Yeah, a few things I just want to say so one thing I think we mentioned is that the perks
Increase access like that is one
Potential benefit of purposes if you can deposit whatever
Whatever currency that an exchange supports, for example bitcoin and the bitmex scenario
Then bitmex can offer exposure to assets that it doesn't necessarily have jurisdiction to issue or actually own
so that is like a benefit of
of perks one question I have is
um, tyler mentioned that maybe perp's benefit price discovery for
four assets, but I just wonder how that price discovery propagates from the
Perp back to the spot asset like on a regulated exchange
Yeah, so I feel like
You know in the example that we just gave where like the first trading of one and two and the spot's trading about hundreds
Yeah, the the market maker or arbitrator has to buy spot in order to shore up their delta head position
Right, they're short on the part
So that buy on like a spot order book will push the price up
And it will you know, the spot will follow the path
okay, and that spot is on so they're not arbitrating it on the
Perp platform instead they're buying this
I mean they could be buying the spot on the perp platform if the perp platform offers the spot asset
But it could be potentially on any platform
and
They they somehow balance
Yeah, the market maker will try to get the best price they can for that
You know, so they'll probably integrate like multiple exchanges and they'll have some flow there and uh, you know
They'll try to get the best price for that delta head position which will necessarily push up the most out of lap price with the perp
The most right and then it just kind of like I think it just goes around like that
And then as a user
like completely removed
What are are there any like risks other than losing all the money you put into a perp?
That and like being liquidated that you could face
Um like investing in perps
So I think as we pointed out before jackson markets when they ever go up
um
And folks have this concept of a funding rate guy, which is like the crowded side of the trade has to pay
Time to train and the crowded side is normally works because markets only go up. So, you know, the longer you hold this perp for
Um, the more, you know, you can end up with shorts. So it's not a perfect synthetic position of your loan, right?
Even if you're a 1x long
um
You know a risk to the user is that yeah, it isn't it isn't the spot, right?
You are paying the funding rate and funding rates can be variable and if markets move a lot the funding rate can move a lot
But I think it's a point decision
Yeah, it sounds like it makes it really difficult
Like even if you're at like 100x leverage or 20x leverage or 10x leverage to predict what your returns would be
if the price moved
to like even to the positive because you don't know what the funding rate would be or like are funding rates variable or they
Fix and if they're variable, what interval do they update? Do you know or does it vary by I mean obviously probably varies by exchange
But what is different?
Yeah, I think it varies by exchange. I think they're getting shorter
Like I think hyper liquid funding rate is much shorter than like the traditional
And if you think about it like there's like a potential funding rate arbitrage here
where like if you are
You know holding the club at the tip of a funding rate right in pain, right? So if it's every four hours every four hours
um
But uh, I think in practice like this it's difficult to actually hit that R because like there's a sell or provide price
uh, and also the note guarantee can get a good entry off of the tape, so
Um, but yeah, I want to think about that. Yeah, well, I feel like we could talk about perks forever
But instead I have a question though. Okay, last question
um
One really interesting thing about purposes that I think we're starting to see some like tradfi adoption of perks
Is that true? Like I feel like I've heard that like perps are launching on like cmv
and stuff like that for like other
Commodities and stuff like that. Do you think that this is?
a true
Innovation outside of the crypto world and like it's superior product. So some of the other
Products that exist and we'll see it be like
the default
I don't know flavor of future
um for
Commodities and stuff where future straightened on it
Yeah, look i'm kind of like a soul for the uh guy
I don't like I think your exact point either about
The collateral that's being disconnected from the spot makes me nervous
Um, so I think as a financial product, it's
Better I think it's more interesting to a certain class of people. Yeah, um
Yeah, you know whether that like
uh
It fills the goals of having a productive financial system and productive debt
asset to their goods. I
You know, I've got my favorite on this which is
Yeah, that's interesting because also I feel like a lot of the people who are trading
Actual futures don't necessarily take physical delivery. They just roll over the contract or something
um
i'm not a super expert in that area at all, but
I guess you have the ability to take physical possession of like the oil or the corn
If you end up holding the contract to the end, but I think there are flavors of futures that are cash settled not
um not physical settled and that is you know, essentially the per mechanism it's like synthetic because
um, it's cash settled, but then you need like a price work goal essentially and if you're you know trading on cme you
Are comfortable using their index prices because they're cme
um
Yeah
What does cme?
Chicago mercantile exchange. I think it's like the biggest futures trading venue
um
Yeah, okay
max, I think I think my concern there is just like, you know when the
The value of your options market is so much bigger than the value, you know, the right spot
I think that this situation is like in india, which jane street famously managed to exploit
But I think like, you know, it's 75 percent of the value. It's just like insane delivery options
Um, and so all the capital close the options and then again, I don't know what the implications are for financial markets
Yeah
That is a crazy thing that most people want to
Use these derivatives instead of just like buy buy the stock or buy the bitcoin
I mean our time preference man. It's short. Yeah
I want money now. I don't want money in 30 years
Who knows if we'll be around?
Oh, you gotta roll the dice get out of the permanent underclass, right? Yeah permanent underclass update time
um
We will live another week at least as the government has yanked away
fable five
Basically like pulling out the heaters from our homes something essential to life
That's pretty crazy. What do you guys think about that? Any thoughts?
Yeah, I just don't know how to how to go on without sweet daddy fable and uh,
Dark uncle mythos
You know helping me do my work and provide abundance
So it's been a rough week
You know first pico's mushrooms and then fable. It's just like come on universe. Why do you why do you give me your greatest toils?
Um, I mean, I think fable is noticeably a better model. There's like this effect where
I logged off friday
And I had like all of these cloud code sessions
And then I logged back on monday and it's been banned and you try to type something and it's like model fable is not working
Switch to opus and then you're like, okay opus pickup where fable left off and opus is like doi
Just clearly not on the same level. It's just not uh
Not you know working on the same thread as as daddy fable was
I left those tabs open for three days because it like I couldn't stomach giving it to dummy opus
After fable had been laying it down for me for like a day
I'm like, I don't want opus to screw it all up, you know
Yeah
You're like a widow that like can't get rid of their spouse's clothing for like years afterwards because that would be like too much closure
And I kept googling is fable bad is fable bad
Yeah, I think the self-esteem damage to this is like making it worse because i've noticed it's like not as good
Maybe it's just like the comparison or maybe it's true
But also maybe jackson you're just like always comparing it to the one that go away. So
Damn. Yeah
Oh and actually opus is probably going to edit this podcast. So
Opus we love you, dude
Uh, no hate and i'm sorry for what we said or what tyler said. It wasn't me
Opus is gonna cut all of my clips to make me sound even dumber than I already am
Just insert all my stock words and like cut things to embarrass me
I actually don't think opus is like such a good good book like clods are like so like warm and well-meaning
You know, like they're like we really care about the world. We're effective altruists robots
um, I do think it would be crazy to work at anthropic because like
they've probably been using
mythos and fable like for I don't know like four months or something and they probably have like
you know like
Fable five four or something because they they keep the best models for themselves and they use it
And then they review they release this nipple fritz to all the plebs like us
And so they were forced to stop using it. It's not just the public
so like if you're like some cracked, um ai
researcher at anthropic and you're like
Oh like this, you know fable was basically doing my job as an ai researcher and it's been doing it for like four months
And then suddenly donald trump rugs you and you have to start using opus for it
You just must feel like you are taken back to the stone age
Um, we only had a you know, like a a brief
shooting star
moment with
With daddy fable, but they really got to know
fable
Yeah, someone described using fable as like smoking crack and i've never smoked crack but i've watched the hunter biden interview
Where he describes it and he said he should sound really heavenly and I felt really good
It was weird. I had nightmares friday night after they took it away
Of like I don't have my life without it. It's just it's tough out there
I think you guys should be a little bit more sensitive to me. Uh, the podcast residents foreign nationally. We may never get to
You know
Be in the sweet embrace of faith ever again
you know, uh, so if I could be
the real member of the
You guys might be okay. Let's do collab today for a minute. We're sorry. We're sorry chris
Yeah, I mean I am worried about what you would do with fable though chris, you know, I feel like I can trust jackson, but you
There's just something i'm like, what are you going to use it for? You know
I have uh, I have your pro australia agenda
Dude, i'm pro korean. What are you talking about? Oh
That's true, you know first we date you guys with the lip histories, uh, like what's next taker loose, uh, they seem great until you get them
led the wise
Have you ever tried to get south korean citizenship or is there a path for you for that?
No, there's not a path for me. No, my father would have had to do it
Um, so not really not an easy path
You have to like
Recursively do it back to your dad
I'd have to like basically immigrate there as if I was not korean
Which is very degrading to my strong korean roots. So I won't end up i'll ever make it
I think it's like a 10 year process for
non
Um, yeah blood koreans which which I am they don't accept you as one of their own but you identify that way
I know probably it's got to be very hurtful probably really freaking out my korean cousins when I was like, yeah
I feel really korean and I don't know how to tell you guys this and they're just like looking at me like dude
Yeah
Yeah, so my cousin she's a quarter korean like me she had a baby. It's an eighth korean and it looks so much more korean
It's like such a rip-off
Is the baby live in korea?
No, no, okay. She's like american coming. She's living in the countryside of georgia babies look like asian though
Sometimes like when when margot came out. I was like she had like dark hair and yeah
I was like she could she could pass off but then
I think they you know, six months later, maybe they look a little bit more like what they look like as adults
I don't know but but she's she's autumn's a year old. She's still looking like like a ginger korean. Yeah
So yeah, it's not
I'm getting mocked about my baby. It happens. Um korean mom
On the talk of babies, you know the korean citizenship. I think like one step up right? It's 0.5
Dude, they're just gonna they're gonna end it up that way. I think they're into the show, dude
Yeah, kind of maybe they would they'll be like come back brown and i'll be like you didn't want me
Yeah, exactly
They're gonna be like this guy is a quarter and he's able to use clogged fable like waiting to get him in the door
Dude, I think that's kind of what's a little spooky about the fables that it's so easy to use
That i'm losing the competitive advantage of being a skilled ai user
Um, do you guys feel that at all? Like I used to think like I still have value because I can cleverly use the ai
But fable was like so good. You don't I don't know how clever you need to be
if you were like
Yeah, I think we had like this beautiful coming line
We were all able to like develop these like skills
And use that as like leverage to change the world
But I think now it's just a new piece of existing. I think we got to like pull someone up and be like, hey
Like, you know that you didn't want to lisa and i'll be like, yeah
I think that's where we're going
You're saying that this is like a preview of them shutting us off from
the
ability to be useful
Yeah, it could be I just I feel like it's like more difficult now
Like, you know the most of that like mechanic is skilled
That really almost all of you like have
Uh, it's just it feels less. I don't know if I was ever a skilled prompter
Like I think I just like talk at it and I just do voice transcription and the transcription like often
like mangles my words
Like you know transcribes the word incorrectly
It sounds stupid. It's just rambling jina thought quite like on this podcast when you listen to me talk
so just imagine me doing that at an ai agent and then the ai agent just has always been able to take that and like
Understand intention extremely well
Um, but yeah, I do think that
The smarter models are able to like execute
So much better and maybe they're able to take like really mangled input and infer from that and just take it and run with it
as well
Yeah, right. So like I feel like even my like
okay, exactly function stream is like
It's just like
Yeah, I I don't know. Well, we'll see but I think I feel like it's a good time to have a platform
Uh, maybe like a difficult time to be
An incumbent in some ways, but uh, but not the problem
Is our podcast a platform for an incumbent?
Uh
Yeah, no, I think I did. No, I think yeah, we're definitely like we're very famous. So I think we're good
This is our hedge
against uh
our tech jobs
basically
Yeah. Yeah, we don't have a way to donate to us yet, but
You know, maybe i'll get on that with uh setting up our payment infrastructure
Um, or maybe one of you guys could take ownership of setting that up
I have a question
We will accept anything. I'll leave it except I don't know like bananas
I guess but not too many
Oh, yeah, that's true. I forget you just despise
Um
Wow
well
The podcast is
Is slaying it down, but I think we're gonna have to wait, you know put it to a close
There were two things we meant to talk about today, but we didn't
number one is
Uh tyler and I is controversial
or not controversial
Hot takes yeah contrarian takes the contrarian corner for tyler and I and then number two is agentic payments
Um, I think there's a lot to talk about there. Maybe that'll be the big talk next next episode
But I think we'll have to call it
Call it now. Does anyone want to have any final farewells to our guests?
uh
Have a good flight back chris
Hey, well, what's happening? Am I like not getting back into the country? You guys know something?
No, dude your final farewell
No, no, you're good, man, you're good. We'll write you a letter. Yeah, the doctor's name
Our stick is that someone is always dialing it over the laptop
So he sabotaged your trip back just to ensure next week. We have one laptop person
Yeah, it makes sense. It makes sense. I'll take one
All right, and everybody be sure to drop a like a five star review on spotify a comment on spotify or youtube
And subscribe slash follow on spotify or youtube
Help us out
Donate when we can accept donations. All right
We're going hot