All right, who are we sharing this podcast with, by the way?
The world.
Are we promoting it to our work colleagues?
Of course, yeah.
That's our first users.
All right, well, let's get into it.
Topic number one, the news.
What has the shakeout revealed in the AI rotation?
The crypto shakeout and the rotation of capital towards AI.
That's right.
Exactly.
I don't know.
I think it's a bit scary, right?
Everybody, I think, there was this talk about the super cycle, but I don't know if that's
what's happening now.
It seems like the capital is going and a lot of people are scared that it's not coming
back, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, Tyler, you brought up some fear about this earlier this week.
Would you share your thoughts?
Oh, man.
I mean, the first sort of thing is just that, like, the money printer isn't ripping right
now.
So Bitcoin and hard assets aren't necessarily going to run when that happens.
And here I was thinking that they're going to lower rates sometime in the future.
You know, Trump is going to change out the people at the Fed.
He's got this new guy that's like his dude in the Fed.
He's going to run the economy hot because Trump loves low rates.
Bitcoin is going to have its big bull market.
And then Trump just decides to start this insane war in Iran and just kick off a whole
huge round of inflation.
So now we've got to keep rates high and that is going to hurt all these assets, obviously.
And so that's like one thing I think that's kind of where a lot of the liquidity is gone.
But then you also kind of simultaneously have this thing happening where obviously there's
a lot of hype and there's kind of like a bubble going on with AI stocks and AI investment
and all this stuff.
So that's like taking a lot of the world's attention, a lot of that like marginal dollar,
that kind of thing.
That makes Bitcoin and crypto look kind of like not only boring, but people are like
that was supposed to be the thing that you could potentially invest in if you were feeling
like bullish, maybe like a little bit like risk-loving.
And now all that attention has gone from like mean stocks into these AI stocks and all this
other stuff.
And so it's like, why would you buy Bitcoin if rates are going to stay elevated and AI
stocks are just ripping because that's the new narrative.
So I think that's taken a lot of the wind out of the sales of Bitcoin from a market
sense.
But you know, that's not necessarily what we're here for.
We're here for the tech.
Am I right, Jackson?
Yeah, absolutely.
I do wonder on that note about being here for the tech.
I've been here for the tech for a long time, and that's why I'm still here.
But has anything changed fundamentally, do you think, with the narrative of Bitcoin and
I guess to a lesser extent stablecoins, or is the utility still there?
And we're just kind of like riding out another one of these like famous crypto liquidity
waves.
I think most likely it's just kind of like riding out another one.
That's how I feel.
But also this one feels a little bit different to me.
I think the main thing to me is like, I feel like people kind of always like one of the
cheap values or something like Bitcoin is like this store of value.
And it's kind of like this thing that stays valuable when like times are scary.
And there's like a lot of tumultuous stuff going on in the world.
And then AI potentially paints this totally different future in a way where it's like
in the modern economies, we have these like debt problems where our debt was growing faster
than our GDP, and we're spending more than GDP growth, therefore we're getting more and
more debt over time.
And when that was like an equation that could never work, I think now we might have had
this like magic thing happen where we have this crazy technology that could actually
bend the GDP growth trajectory to where it kind of bails out all those governments.
And suddenly we don't have that thing where they have to run the money printers to pay
off the debt because the economy is just ripping so hard.
And so then it's like, what is the role of a store value asset in that case where people
aren't feeling the pain of inflation quite as bad?
I think that kind of like takes a little bit of a narrative out of it.
And in general, it's kind of like, what is the role of a kind of like cover your ass
asset in a world where there is potentially like this new abundance, huge economic growth,
and like a lot of like optimism and just kind of like good feels.
And that's like a great world.
I think that's the world we all want to live in.
But maybe that isn't a world that's compatible with like Bitcoin as this kind of like hedge
against all that crazy stuff.
I don't know.
So that's some stuff I've been thinking about lately is like, maybe a bunch of us were just
super kind of pessimistic and cynical about where the world was headed in this economic
way.
And like, I'm not saying this is guaranteed to happen, but it's like some thing that is
in the possibility space now, and just thinking about that and thinking about what does that
world look like kind of makes me question the role of Bitcoin a little bit.
But yeah, I don't think that's like my base case is just like a possibility.
Right.
So you're basically wondering, like, well, you know, where are we if we can actually
like outbuild the debt?
Like, what does that mean for Bitcoin?
Yeah.
And just like, you know, if we have like the country of geniuses in a data center, whatever
the unprofit people promise us, which kind of looks like we're headed there based on,
you know, Fable and all these new models just completely being smarter than all of us.
Well, at least smarter than me.
I don't know about you guys, you're more gigabrand, definitely outpacing.
But yeah, I mean, it's like if you can produce, you know, goods and services, like super cheap,
because in 10 years we have like robot armies of workers that are just producing everything
we need.
I don't know, like maybe you're not thinking too hard about preserving your wealth because
of material abundance.
Maybe that's a little reductive.
I haven't thought it through that detailed.
I do.
I wonder if that creates like a stronger incentive for the like self sovereign money narrative
though, right?
Like, you know, in this sort of like world where everything's churning, you know, there
are like a lot of different currencies competing and a lot of different things competing for
your attention and and for your capital.
Yeah, I do.
I do wonder if there's like a potential of that self sovereign money narrative, but that's
a half, half baked thought on my part, I think.
Yeah, I mean, I definitely love that thought more than like the currency of the future
being like your anthropic API credits, basically, or whatever, like that's the new, like the
active currency for the world.
You know, I still like the idea and like it appeals to me, it's always going to appeal
to me this idea of Bitcoin is this kind of like neutral freedom money that is kind of
like for the internet, by the internet for the people by the people not controlled by
any group of specific, like small, powerful people.
That idea is always going to appeal to me, but maybe I've become a little bit more like
bearish or cynical about like the extent to which there's enough people in the world that
actually care about those ideals to like scale it to where it actually becomes something
that is, you know, like the default or like the new standard or it's like inevitable.
Like I really do question how many like if, if the number go up thing kind of like goes
away or gets weakened, then all you have left is the true believers and I just don't think
there's enough of those people who think that way about this stuff.
I would like there to be more, but I'm not going to change my mind on that, on my like
principles and what I believe about what should be in the world, but like what should be or
what ought to be as different than like what is, I guess.
Yeah.
I mean, it seems like there could also be like a coordination problem that Bitcoin could solve.
Like I mean, in the, in the world that you're proposing where like anthropic, you know, tokens
are like some type of currency, right?
Like they're not fungible with open AI tokens.
I mean, and this is a, this is a dark, dark thought it's fair experiment, but I always
thought that like, you know, Bitcoin was like in some ways there to solve like the coordination
problem of money.
And yeah, I don't know if maybe like it has a role in the future where like there are
multiple types of money.
Yeah, I think it could.
But also you have this like future, like maybe the future where there's this abundance and
optimism is like a high trust world and people trust the government fiat currencies.
And then you're even seeing like basically the leaders of the AI companies are essentially
inviting the government to like take shares from them, which is a really weird state of
affairs.
And I feel like people are like into that idea, not so much like I don't really want
the government to own big parts of like private corporations, even if they're super important,
I want like the benefits of the technology that they're building to be like wildly dispersed.
But I feel like having the government take a big stake is probably the wrong structural
way to go about that.
But like you can imagine a future where like the government has this huge stake in these
companies and they're kind of like, I don't know, like merged together in some kind of
creepy dystopian way.
And then they support fiat currencies or, you know, like, that's just they're not going
to necessarily be embracing Bitcoin if they're like so tied up with the government and fiat
life.
For sure.
I mean, it's not even clear to me that that would be a good thing, but just like just
a thought experiment about like what I understood Bitcoin, one of the problems that Bitcoin
initially seems to be solving like a native currency for the Internet.
I've heard many say, but in this like dystopian world you're talking about where the government
and like, let's say there's like three companies that control all the intelligence and make
all the money.
What is dystopian about about that?
Like if the companies make so much money, they make all the money and then we have nothing
to do.
So we need money or food or whatever.
Is it bad if the government is like suckling that money so then they can disperse it to
the people?
I mean, if they disperse it, right?
I feel like this is the from from what I understand it to be.
I feel like that's the argument about the permanent underclass right where like previously
like some form of like your utility and your participation in society has been hinged on
labor.
And as that asymptotes the value of that asymptotes towards zero, there's no longer any reason
to sustain you, you know, I don't I don't know if that's true.
That's that's just what I've heard.
From some people.
What do you mean to sustain you like that will die on the underclass will die on potentially.
I don't know.
But dark.
I think I think people are like scared of like an ossifying right like the sort of social
status of people and maybe more importantly power also fine.
Yeah, I think it's like the value of labor in any form, whether it be cognitive labor
or like physical labor, basically goes to zero because everything can be done better
by machines and machines are basically capital whether it's like a robot or like a bunch
of GPUs in a data center, those are capital.
And so there's a world where like the returns to label labor are basically nil and the returns
to capital are compounding and that's kind of what matters.
And so if you think about a world like that, I think that's a very extreme thing.
I don't think it's necessarily going to be that black and white.
But if you think about that, then it's basically like the wealth distribution among people
is going to be basically frozen by what amount of capital they had when the value of labor
went to zero because there's like no way to acquire more capital with your labor because
your labor is worthless.
So the only way to get more capital is to have capital at that event horizon.
But yeah, I'm proud of us that we went 12 minutes into the pod before we mentioned program
underclass.
I'm sorry.
There was me.
I was trying really hard not to say the P word, but just like it kind of like it begged
it begged its own question.
I think it should be a recurring topic.
You know, I think we need to get our memes going for the podcast.
We need to keep it light.
I think we jumped right into like a little doomsday scenario for me.
I want to I want to take it back.
I want to get a little bit more fun.
Yeah, we should be more fun.
But yeah, we will remember the topic, the permanent underclass.
We can do weekly updates.
And I think this is actually a great way to segue into Claude's new release fable.
You know, is this the inflection point?
Is it over for us?
Tyler, you mentioned that the AI is smarter than you and asked if it's smarter than us.
It is no denying it.
It's totally cracked.
I got it to build an Android or an iOS app and it built like wrote all the code without
like being able to test it while I installed Xcode.
It just started writing Swift code like a like a gangster and it did it in like 10 minutes.
So it's definitely better than us.
Building is not the it's not the problem with your app.
What is your app idea?
If you share it, I don't know if you want to leak alpha on our first podcast like this.
I'll leak some alpha.
The alpha was that I for looped Claude and said I want to be a millionaire.
So do market research and find something we can build so I can become a millionaire.
And every time you loop reread your progress so you can like iterate.
And in like three loops we had an iOS application.
It has to do with farming, but we don't like like you said we don't want to leak alpha.
Main Street's looking for this, they're trying to.
It's a big market.
They're trying to trade.
Yeah.
10 is 11 million Americans.
Spoiler.
Don't look at what 11 million Americans do.
That's public information.
But this is I mean, it's crazy.
This is like a huge step up from even Claude 4.6 sonnet whatever that I was using until
Monday of this week when I upgraded my Claude.
Like it's unreal.
You don't even have to be specific.
But are you a millionaire yet?
Not yet.
It's only been an hour and 15 minutes.
The day is young.
But how many times can I ask Claude to do this?
You know, I could ask you to do this 30 times and it's much better than me.
So one in, you know, 30 times we should at least make like $10.
And that's enough.
Yeah.
You might need more than a million dollars to get out of the permanent hundred class
these days.
It's sad.
What is the price?
How many apps that I'm not allowed to talk about what the app is about and how many of
those hypothetically, you know, do you need?
Well, I'm going for the subscription based model.
So I'm looking to get like, let's say if I get 100 users and they're each paying like
$1 a month and this app cost me, I don't know, $10 a month to maintain, then I don't know,
I'm making $1,200 a year.
Maybe I can arbitrage, you know, the place that I'm living and then I only need like
two or three of these.
I don't know.
Is there a place where you can live for 10,000 US dollars a year?
I'm sure there are.
Bangkok.
Yeah.
Potentially.
No, maybe not even.
Yeah.
But I mean, the principle remains, you know, and we're like accelerating the AI is insane.
We're privileged to work in tech and to work at a company that forces us to use AI.
The people that like aren't using AI every day and don't see this, it's going to be shocking
to them.
I think when it comes around, I guess when is that going to happen?
Because still some people haven't even tried chat GPT.
I think one thing I've noticed about Fable that I didn't notice as much with the previous
models is like, so I always try to make the model do as much of my job as I possibly can.
Like, you know, I outsourced to it for the code writing, but also like for ideation,
like architectural patterns, like whatever, I like I try to run it through the model and
see if it can come up with anything.
I think like Fable for me is the first one where I barely have to moderate its ideas.
Like it's capable of like doing the executive step and then also doing the mechanical implementation
step and bundling it together because the context window is so big as well.
It like, you know, like you're talking about with your million dollar app idea, you know,
it's one hour a single session.
It's capable of like orchestrating this entire complex task.
So I think for me, like that was a big, like big step up.
Yeah, it's that shift from like, I don't know, a few months ago where you have to say, make
this use this, you know, look in this area to do this.
And now you can just say do this and it will figure out where to look and won't make mistakes.
It's crazy.
It makes me wonder, like if like the edge in some of these markets, you know, goes back
to this, like I think that, you know, there was a brief time where there was like some
edge about like coming up with strategies based on unintuitive relationships between
things.
But maybe it just goes straight back to like inside information.
I don't know.
Maybe that's the only edge that's left.
I'm not sure.
Yeah, it's just being one of the companies that have these models for months before they
give them to everyone else.
Right.
A hundred percent.
If you train the model and you have access to it and you only give it up after you've
like basically armed all of the low hanging fruit that it can generate, you know, all
the new drugs that can discover all the hacks it can do, but they probably won't do that.
I don't know.
They'll probably just do the good things of it, which is great.
They're going to give us new drugs that solve disease and other stuff, but it does seem
like the homogenization of this kind of value where it's like there's a couple of companies
that can only be producing this crazy cutting edge models that can then generate all this
value, like the value accrual and the value centralization, and it's just potentially
insane.
Hold up.
Let's go back to what you said.
You said there looks like they're only going to do the good things.
How did they convince you that that's what they're going to do?
Well, they're not going to like use, you know, mythos to like rug all the defy protocols
that need to be rugged, right?
Like they, I guess they're trying to be a little bit white hat about it, at least in
those cases.
What would be an example of a bad thing that you could, you could see them doing?
I just feel like it's like, A, I feel like actually the gains to doing bad things are
lower.
Like why would you spend all your time trying to run defy protocols when you can like invent
a new drug or something?
Like I don't think that there's really much, you know, like the highest value, bad things
that you can do with these models is probably less than the highest value.
Good things.
Maybe that's optimistic.
Take.
This is like conspiratorial and I apologize, but I was talking to my boy yesterday.
We need conspiratorial on this podcast.
That's the only way we're going to get miles to listen.
Yeah.
Well, one of my boys works.
He did like bioinformatics doctorate at UW and works in biotech and he was trying to use
fable for his job and it won't answer any of his questions like regarding biology, which
is like, you know, a hard, a pretty hard science.
So the reason I had mentioned this is like these companies that are making the models
and as we grow our dependence on these models, they have like a really strong ability to,
to control the truth.
Like what we believe is the truth.
So when they like refuse to answer questions regarding a certain subject, like that should
remind you that they also can like push information regarding certain subjects that they want
to push.
I'm not saying that they're doing that, but like, but they probably are, you know, we
just wouldn't know.
For sure, I think there's like a, also a profit incentive there.
Like, you know, people have talked to death about like embedding advertisements within
large language models or like, you know, people are quite suggestible in general I would say.
One thing about the bio, the biomedical angle.
So I was thinking about this the other day and I like texted my friends.
I was like, Hey man, like, do you think like a anthropic is going to sell like a mega tier
subscription of my thoughts to Eli Lilly?
Or do you think that they would just come up with like the wonder the mega drug themselves?
And so I asked Gemini of course, who is, you know, maybe a little bit biased being a competing
model and apparently anthropic acquired a wet lab for 400 mil not very long ago.
So it seems like maybe, you know, there are thoughts about going the vertical angle.
And I kind of wonder what that world looks like, where like anthropic and open AI are
these like fat zaibatsu companies like developing all of this stuff.
I don't know.
Yeah, I guess this is exactly what what Tyler was saying is because they have access to
the model so far in advance, they could monopolize intelligence, intelligence jobs or whatever
research opportunities.
That's crazy.
Yeah, I wonder what they're I mean, they think they're actually training models all the time
with all the compute that they have or do you think I mean, I think what we're suggesting
is that they're sometimes they're using all those data centers and energy they have to
like, use the models to to make money in other ways, maybe so like maybe that's why fable,
like we only get it for 10 days, you know, and then they're they're gonna roll that compute
all that training data back into fable to whatever.
Yeah, what do you do at table five, bro?
Sorry, fable 5.2.
Yeah, Tyler, how about what, what is your experience been with fable this week?
You've been trying, right?
Yeah, I've been fabling a lot.
I mean, it's super strong, I think it's a little slow.
Is what I've kind of found.
I wonder if they're just having capacity issues.
I think it's super interesting that they were like, a couple months back, they were like,
mythos is too powerful to release to the world.
We can't possibly do that.
And then there were like a bunch of rumors that anthropic basically had like under invested
in compute and didn't have enough compute to keep up with the demand for their products,
which to be fair, is probably insane and unprecedented.
But then they signed this big deal with SpaceX to buy the cluster that Elon built colossus,
I think it's called in Tennessee.
And they basically like day Elon gave them all of his compute, and then they were able
to like, raise all their limits for everyone and then like fable comes like a week later.
So I do feel like some of that was posturing where they were like, this model is too dangerous
to release.
And it was really like, we don't have the compute resources to release this giant model.
And then once they did, they were like, okay, now we're going to drop it on the world.
And basically just completely MOG, open AI, am I using that word correctly?
I don't know.
Absolutely.
I think it would be like AI of like the AI of the group, not the alpha male of the group.
I know, but we got to give Tyler some credit.
That's very hip for the times.
I'm the old man, you know, of the team.
But yeah, I've been using it.
I think it's really good.
I mean, I'll be fair, like I hadn't really done, like I hadn't tested like Opus, for
example, with some like really ambitious kind of work.
But this week I was like, here's a whole PRD for this feature that like I want us to build
for a cash app, and like instead of maybe breaking it down piece by piece, and like
doing all this, I was like, read the PRD, like literally create all the draft PRs that
are needed, sequence out all the exact work that needs to happen.
If there's like client code that needs to change, you need to like build the app, and
like test the flows, and take like videos of the flows and all this stuff, make no mistakes.
And it just like, ripped for like a day, I had to press yes, and accept all permissions
like 20 times, even though I told them to dangerously skip permissions.
And then eventually, I just was like, here's like seven PRs drafted.
And all of our repos, I'm like probably spamming them and all the engineers hate me.
And it's like, just spring and slop.
But Fable was like, we have done it, the feature is ready.
I think that does kind of bring like a really interesting question, which is like, if these
models can do like, basically that end to end stuff, then like, I think the biggest
challenge is that last mile of like actually shipping the thing.
And that is partly an engineering problem, but also it's like, very much like a coordination
problem, like working within the system, knowing the process, doing all the right things kind
of problem.
And that stuff is all I think, super time consuming and like a little bit kind of like,
like tacit knowledge from the people who have navigated that process before.
And so it's interesting if AI can like, in theory, enable somebody to build a feature
end to end, like, in a week, and get most of the way there.
But then it's like, have you actually just take this kind of like black box work, and
then actually get it to where we're comfortable shipping it?
That's I think a problem I haven't really seen solve that well.
And I think it kind of requires like, obviously, like our engineers who are working on other
things to like, stop and like, start reviewing all these slot PRs that I'm putting together.
And like, that probably isn't a great request for them from me.
So yeah, I don't know how to square that circle.
I was just gonna say, you know, Jackson and I were chatting just earlier about how imminent
obsolescence, and I think like we came to like a similar conclusion, like Jackson said
something like, we're all just kind of like, SREs now, like, but like, like, to exactly
your point, Tyler, like, I think, like the last mile finishing seems to be bigger and
bigger part of the role.
Yeah, I don't have any, any more thoughts.
I just thought it was like really interesting that you both came to the same conclusion.
Yeah, but this is interesting.
I think, like, within the company that all three of us happen to work in, but we have
no affiliation with.
I think they're working on like the things that will help you get through that last mile.
That's like CI, AI driven code reviews, and then like, automating the testing as much
as possible.
For example, I imagine for you, Tyler, it's not trivial to like, run an Android emulator
to test the feature that you just built locally on your computer, but you know, the teams
are building things that make that testing like, seamless and quick.
And that is really the right direction to be moving in this AI world where we want everything
to happen automatically.
And then all Chris and I as engineers will be left to do is like, respond if there is
a bug that the AI code reviews missed, or that you missed when you were manually testing
the product in your, I don't know, yeah, in your manual testing step.
I will say like, I know, like, Fable is really great, and it can like understand how to scale
services and like, think about like, concurrency and race conditions and so on and so forth.
But I, I'm still not sure that it has like, a good way to like, unify and like, create
like a good architecture that won't create problems in the future.
It's a small piece, but I don't know, maybe Fable 5.2, as we've said, which is what the
next model is called, we'll fix that.
Yeah.
Damn, yeah, Tyler, as someone who's not an engineer, how long do you think me and Chris
have?
What's the prognosis?
I don't know, Matt, I mean, you guys might be best positioned to ride this wave better
position than people with other skill sets coming into it, you know, like maybe a lot
of the roles in the tech world are kind of converging, and it's just eventually going
to be like one position, which is just like AI whisper, you know, but maybe the best AI
whispers are people who come at it from a technical background, or maybe they're people
who come at it from like a product background, or they can like know what to build and give
really good feedback and direction, or it's people who come at it from a data science
background, because obviously, that's my background, and I think that's going to be the winning
one.
I mean, I don't think that provides any particular advantage over those ones, but I think we're
all cooked, man.
I mean, just got to, you know, embrace the world model block as a consciousness thing
and we'll be set.
I will say it's forcing me to think differently as an engineer, like I'm having to like spread
out my, you know, cognition in order to like both be able to like stay productive, but
also just like feeling out the shape of this new role that you're talking about, Pylo.
Like, you know, there are like, and I imagine it's like different depending on what role
you're coming from, but there are like places where I'm very comfortable, which is like
the core engineering stuff, and then there are places where I'm like much less comfortable,
which is like the more like core product thinking stuff.
And yeah, it's just like, I'm having to be like way more cognitively flexible than I'm
used to.
I don't know if anyone else is feeling that, but that's my whole take.
What would be your guys' jobs if you weren't working at a computer?
Chicken farmer.
Hey, come on.
I don't know, it depends, like is it me right now as a 29-year-old man with the skills that
I have today, or is it like me starting over either in college or just out of college?
Tyler.
However you interpret it, like what would you do, yeah, what job are you suited for?
I mean, I've got a real estate license in Georgia, so I would consider being a real
estate agent.
I think it's chill to like talk to people and try to sell them stuff, but like also
real estate comes with a lot of ethical issues, and you're supposed to be like a guide, and
I think I could lean into being a good person and talking to strangers.
All right.
Tyler, do you have any ... I mean, my favorite job I've ever had was being
a lifeguard.
That was like my summer job in high school and college, the amazing job these days.
You just like hang out on the beach, potentially help people, kind of look at the water, maybe
you like rake some sand.
Especially with those abs, you know.
You're looking good out there.
Hell yeah.
You know, it'd just be more incentive to get that tan, get that sun life, solar worshipper,
but maybe lifeguards are going to be replaced by flock cameras and drones that come and
plop you out of the water, and they won't be lifeguards anymore.
Who knows?
Yeah, who wins the lifeguard replacement race?
Is it Elon with the humanoid robots, or is it Amazon with the drone delivery?
Is it Andrew with the submarine that just like explodes and you're in trouble, I don't
know.
I actually think I would ... I actually like being a Slut Vibe Coder.
I think it's a great job.
I don't know if this job is going away, but yeah, it's fun, it's very fun to orchestrate
it, but first of all, agreed, this is the best our job has ever been, for me.
It's not close.
Writing the code was super boring.
Thinking about solving the problem is definitely the more fun thing, but you're missing the
point of the question.
Tyler said you can't be in a computer, so you have to do something different.
We've got open whisper, and so I don't have to physically be ...
So you'd be talking through a red solo cup on a string to your computer, outside?
I would use a cloud mobile, and I would be like, "Hey, Claude, what's up?
What are we doing, big dog?"
And then we would go back and forth.
That was beautiful.
Calling your phone not a computer is quite a stretch, Chris.
Okay, we're getting picky, it's down to semantics, all right, that's fine.
I'd find a way.
That phone would have been the most powerful computer in the world 30 years ago.
That's so true, and now it can't even run Fable 5, so what's the point of it?
For now.
Yeah, I mean, if we continue our chip improvement process, or whatever, I have no idea, totally
hypothetical.
Will we be able to run a cloud on our phone?
We won't need to.
No one will ever need to, but will it be possible to be running a cloud on a phone in 30 years?
I feel like I would not like to continue blasting every thought I have to anthropic seders like
at every hour of the day.
I wouldn't hate local models.
Local models are cool.
Have you tried any?
Oh, Quinn.
Quinn?
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, I think that they've all been sufficient for the task that I've tackled personally,
but not at work.
I never tried to throw it at a big code problem.
What did you use it for?
Yeah, the same as you.
I was wondering if I could replace my code subscription.
I couldn't.
Although, I have thought about putting Quinn on my ... I have a frigate box in my apartment
that controls the lights.
I think it would be very funny to let Quinn have a go, turn the lights on and off.
I'm sure other people have thought like that, but maybe I'll ask people to do it this weekend.
Nice.
All right.
I'm going to transition out of the AI topic.
Maybe we'll do our cold open now, now that we're feeling warm.
What is the name of our podcast?
I feel like I'm waiting for Tyler to do this.
Yeah, Tyler.
Tyler, where are you at, man?
I thought you guys had decided this in my absence at the office.
You had so many good ideas, though.
I feel like you set an expectation.
Was it bits, bots, and bucks?
That was the triple B. That's one option.
I feel like you want to use words that are real, so then people might accidentally stumble
upon our podcast.
All right, so no couch.
Yeah, no couch.
No couch.
No permanent under-couch.
Under-couch.
I don't know.
Tyler, what's your opinion?
Do we want to lean into the fact that we work for Block?
Is that our primary thing?
No, I think we should lean away from that.
Okay, so this is like a publicly available podcast that we're doing, not affiliated with
Block, even though you're recording it from a couch in the Block offices.
This could be any couch.
Yeah, dude.
Come on.
This could be any couch in the way.
I'm sorry I doxxed your couch location.
Yeah, dude.
We're going to get attacked.
We're live.
I don't have a permanent underpod.
Permanent underpod?
I think that's kind of funny.
Okay.
Just permanent underpod or the permanent underpod?
Underpod is one word or two words?
It's like hyphenated, maybe, with an M dash.
That would be fine.
We're going to do permanent underpod, no B.
No B.
All right.
We're live.
Welcome, everybody, to the permanent underpod.
My name is Jackson.
My name is Chris.
And I'm Tyler.
And we will be your hosts.
First we'll go through what each of us brings to the table.
I'll start.
I'm Jackson.
I don't bring a lot to the table, but I am the acting expert in the Korean financial
markets.
Nice.
Okay.
I'm Chris.
I've done quite a bit of work on stablecoins and decentralized exchanges.
So I guess I'm that guy and Tyler?
Yeah.
Hey, everyone.
I'm Tyler.
I guess if I had one work focus, it would be Bitcoin data and then also maybe Bitcoin
payments and Bitcoin Lightning Network, although for people who claim that they focus on the
Bitcoin Lightning Network, I'd say that I'm probably like 10th percentile at best in terms
of intelligence and knowledge there.
So I'll take that with a great assault.
Thank you, our humble Bitcoin/Lightning x-ray.
But tell me, Chris, why should we trust you when it comes to stablecoins?
You shouldn't.
You shouldn't trust anyone when it comes to stablecoins.
Yeah.
That's a red ocean.
I don't know.
So I've worked sort of like in an adjacent part of the stack since like maybe 21, 22.
I originally worked on a very early cross-chain decentralized exchange, which has had a bit
of traction.
So I've seen a lot of stuff happen.
I've seen people rise and fall.
I've seen people trade mackerel in prison for various favors.
I mean, not personally, but like, you know, I've been...
Video chat?
Yeah.
I mean, if you told me, that would be awesome.
That would be great for the public.
Yeah.
Have him on as a guest.
Yeah, for sure.
I'm sure he would say yes.
So yeah, I don't know if you should trust me, but I've definitely, I've definitely seen
some stuff.
And why should we trust you, Tyler, when it comes to Bitcoin data and the Lightning Network?
You know, I don't know about trust, you can verify.
Verify?
Okay.
Well, how can we verify you?
Yeah.
Tell us.
I guess that one's hard too, because a lot of my contributions have mostly just been
working for a private company, which is Block.
But yeah, I worked on Bitcoin and Block for like five to six years.
I used to do some public research on Bitcoin data under a NIMM on Twitter, and it was like
half like bull porn, like why the number will go up next month.
No way.
Because like the on-chain data is flashing.
And then I kind of used that as a way to like get some followers, and then I'd have these
like other blog posts that were really underperforming that would be like, what is a Poisson distribution?
And like, why does that factor into Bitcoin mining data?
And like, nobody wanted to read those ones.
So that's a little bit of proof of work.
I have a blog from like 2020-2019 talking about that kind of stuff.
That's it.
I don't know.
I mean, I've been paying attention to Bitcoin for over 10 years and like working on it for
at least half of that.
So I know a little bit, but not a lot.
Dude, I've known you for years.
I trust you more now than ever.
This is amazing.
A quick plug for Chris.
Chris also has a blog.
We'll talk about that later.
Don't read that.
But I think what Tyler was saying is a great transition.
He's been tracking Bitcoin for years.
So now we're going to talk about our first interactions with some sort of cryptocurrency,
whatever it was.
What is the first cryptocurrency you bought and at what price?
And then what do you use it for?
We'll start with Chris.
I don't have to answer all those questions, right?
Yeah.
That's one question.
What did you buy?
How much was it?
And why?
Why did you buy?
I probably set up a Bitcoin miner in 2016, like on a Raspberry Pi.
I don't think I ever mined anything.
Like, I think I was part of like some pool that I never withdrew from, but I did buy
it around that time.
And then, yeah, I guess I just like sold it to buy like, who can say, like maybe a succulent
Chinese meal or something.
So 2016 you said?
Yeah, that would be.
So what was that, like $400 and it was Bitcoin?
Yeah, it would have been like basically free at that point.
Basically.
Okay.
Yeah, I'll share next.
I bought like $100 of Bitcoin when it was like $300 in 2015.
So I could buy LSD and I bought it and the Bitcoin is gone.
What about you Tyler?
I had a hard follow there.
I mean, that's, I bought, I think some amount of undetermined amount of Bitcoin when it
was $220 or something in 2015.
And the first exposure I got to Bitcoin was when I worked at Google and it was like my
first week there.
And that was like the peak of the 2013 bull market, I want to say.
And one of the guys on my team was like a super early Bitcoiner and he was like that
guy who will make like, he just wouldn't stop talking about Bitcoin ever.
And so he would just kind of Bitcoin fill the whole team and then when the price went
up a bunch, people were like, dude, like I want to buy some Bitcoin.
Can I buy some from you?
And they would like Venmo him like a hundred dollars and he would like go print out a paper
wallet from like the Google printer and then like put a hundred dollars worth of Bitcoin
on it.
And just like leave it at their desk.
And I sat next to this guy and like, uh, I still wasn't into it at that point.
And I was kind of like, this seems kind of crazy because people would be coming by at
like 10 a.m. Oh, I'm going to buy a hundred dollars of Bitcoin and then they'd come back
like a couple hours later and be like, the price went up again.
I need more.
And I was like, this is a little bit too frothy for me.
But then I got pretty close with that guy and heard his Bitcoin takes and Bitcoin pilling
orange filling for like one or two years after that.
And then when Bitcoin went to the bear after that bull, I bought some when the price was
much lower because I was like, maybe this seems like a good time to buy and I bought
mostly as an investment.
But then my first Bitcoin transaction was, uh, I bought, I think some Adderall from like
some Indian company, it was called like modafinil or something.
And they sent me some pills from India that I took, I guess, extensively to like work
harder, which is a really lame thing.
I don't do that anymore.
That's like a mid twenties Tyler.
You're such a good employee, dude.
What the fuck?
That's awesome.
Good job.
Would you say that very expensive Adderall now when you look at it in hindsight, but
was there economic output that like the additional marginal unit of output from the Adderall would
you say it has like in the fullness of time covered the cost of the Bitcoin?
It's hard to say, you know, what my career would have been like if I hadn't taken those
20 doses of Adderall while working as a low-level data scientist at Google in 2015, but, uh,
you know, it got me to where I am today.
You can't argue with path dependence, it just has to be the way it has to be.
Wow.
Thank you.
Yes.
So you don't have any leftover Adderall like 13 years ago.
No.
Did you have some good experiences with your Bitcoin asset though?
Oh, yeah, dude.
I did a lot of a lot of assets in college and I think it was, it was very healthy.
It's a good thing to do.
Um, yeah, I've already told Chris about it, so I'm not going to, not going to tell him
again, but highly recommend good for the, good for the body.
Yeah, I guess at that point, if it was like $100 a Bitcoin at $300 a coin, it's only like
$20,000.
That's like, um, software engineer privilege to say only $20,000, but I think for the mental
health gains, massive, totally worth it.
Nice.
So I'm, I'm hearing that you should, but to sell a student with Bitcoin, don't do that.
That's why we can't say we're a block.
That's why we will talk about the company.
But that also reminds me, we should probably say what this podcast is about.
So this podcast is going to be focused on, uh, Bitcoin stable coins and AI, because that
is our three lives at, you know, at our job and that's what we know.
So if you like those things, you're in the right place.
If you don't like those things, you should leave.
All right, don't leave, like, like, and subscribe anyway, subscribe, press the bell button.
Okay, cool.
Now that we're done with that, we can, we can do some different, oh, we could do another
fun topic, which is the confessional, the biggest bag fumble.
I would, yeah, I would like to hear your guys because I feel like I've, I've said mine like
15 times and it's like no funny, but you'll have to tell the, the people, the people want
to know, but, uh, yeah, I can go first.
I've never made money with, uh, with, uh, these little cryptocurrencies.
Unfortunately, I don't think that it's a good way to make money.
One time I put like $20,000 into loop ring.
I don't, I didn't know anything about loop ring.
I just did it.
Cause, uh, one of my buddies made like six figures on, was it O-M-G?
O-M-G, and I'm like, okay, this guy knows what he's talking about.
So I threw down 20 grand on loop ring and then I sold it at like 10 grand.
So I lost $10,000, but I don't know, you know, it is what it is.
Maybe this is too financially forthright, go ahead, Tyler.
All right, I'm actually pulling up some receipts right now.
Yeah.
I can give you, I can give you two.
One is a real one and one is a hypothetical one.
Okay.
So the hypothetical one is, um, I interviewed at open AI in 2018 back when they were probably
like a 30 person company and probably the, if I had not fumbled that interview, the compensation
package on that job is like probably worth like hundreds of millions of dollars or something.
Um, but I was completely unqualified for the job and didn't prepare for the interview.
And so when I joined it, they were like, do you want to be a, do you want to be an AI
researcher?
And I was like, no, like I'm like a data scientist, let me do AB tests and like, I can like maybe
do some, uh, transfer learning on pre-grained models, but not I think the stuff you're doing.
And they wanted me to tell them about my favorite paper in AI and go deep into it and explain
why I liked it.
And I had no answer for that cause I had never written it or never read an AI paper.
I just like act on data.
Um, so that's a bad one.
And then the financial one that was real is apparently on November 30th, 2020, I bought
I think $20,000 worth of Bitcoin call options with a strike price of $75,000 for that expired
a year later and, um, okay, no, I bought yeah, about the cent that $20,000 worth.
And then that was right before the bull runs.
You might think like sick, you actually made a lot of money on that.
I think they went up in value, like something like five X, they went up to like a hundred
thousand dollars and they were still not in the money, but I could have sold them for
like a huge profit, but I was like, no, surely the bull market is going to rip even higher.
And so I'm going to hold onto them cause they still have like six or seven months left before
they expire.
And then I think the, by the time they expired, they expired out of the money.
And so they went from like 20,000 to a hundred thousand to zero.
And that's why I don't do options anymore.
Follow up question.
How often do you think about each of these?
Like, do you ever or, uh, the Bitcoin one pretty much never with the call options because
it's whatever, um, like obviously I'd rather have $20,000, but also like, uh, you know,
in the grand scheme of like the category of money that I put into cryptocurrency or Bitcoin,
I think I'm like probably ahead or at least like break even not embarrassingly down.
So it's all, you know, one, one game.
Uh, and then the other one, not too much because I don't think I was actually like even qualified
for that job.
And then also it would have been like, okay, you get the job, but then do you like stay
working there for like multiple years while like they didn't have like their shit figured
out or like a good product until like literally like four or five years after that.
I think they had fired a bunch of people.
They were like, Elon was going to like rub all their money.
So like the, the idea that I would have gotten that job, but I was not qualified for done
good enough work that they wanted to keep me.
And then I would have survived all that time working there and like come out the other
end of it in this like life changing situation is very, um, impractical.
So I don't think that that one is too bad.
I mean, for, for what it's worth, I'm like honored to be on the same permanent underclass
life boat as, as you, uh, I mean, it's, I mean, it's sad that you didn't get a ticket
to first boss, but yeah, that thanks for staying around this podcast with my consolation prize.
Dude, you're, you're such an elite.
This is crazy.
Yeah.
It's like, I don't know if I'm too young, but I'm just never, nothing's happened.
Nothing good like that was ever happened or like potentially good.
Everything has been like, okay, um, I can tell mine, um, which is just like a very classic
shit coining story.
Um, so like in the COVID lockdowns, like 2021, uh, I was in Berlin in my parliament between
jobs.
Uh, and I was like, I wanted to do some side projects, uh, and I came up with this like
just completely degenerate idea to scrape all of these, uh, sources of like crypto sentiment
data.
Like everything was ripping at the time.
It seemed like impossible to not make money.
And I just like wrote about that, like, you know, it took, took all these mentions, like
put them on a spark line.
Uh, you did like a bag of words sentiment model and then just like picked basically
ended up just picking the ones that were mentioned the most, uh, and like bought a bag of them
like $300 worth.
Uh, and it bought like all these like terrible coins, like one was called like donut.
Uh, and one of the ones that bought was, uh, was she but you knew, uh, and like, uh, it
was so early to it, right?
It's like, I think the way this works is like when they start running these pump and dump
schemes, they just like blast it out everywhere.
So it just like went from zero to like the only spark line that mattered.
Uh, and, uh, yeah, like I bought $300 of it.
Like two weeks later, I like looked at what this bot had done and I was like, I would
prefer to have $300 than $0 and I like sold it at like a slight loss.
Uh, and then, you know, a month or two later, uh, that bag was worth like $8 million.
So that was like it, like, you know, I, I don't know what the lesson there is.
Like trust yourself, like, you know, put it all on red.
I don't know.
Uh, but yeah, that's, that was, that was my, uh, probably my biggest one.
Two months away from $8 million, $300 to $8 million, which is just like when, when you
think about it in percentage points, uh, yeah, a little bit, a little bit disappointing.
How much do you think about that?
Um, I used to think about it a lot, but it's like, it's so far in the past now that like,
you know, I'm just, I'm, I'm resigned to, uh, to, you know, what circumstances would
you think, would you be like going to sleep and be like, I think so I used to have like
a very difficult job and I would be like sitting at my desk reading, like, I could just not
do this.
Like, if I just didn't like wake up that one day and want like $300 for like go on those
one, uh, I think we all know why.
Yeah.
100%.
Oh man.
That's painful.
Thank you.
Wow.
I hope that humanizes us to our viewers.
Also I wanted to.
Did you give one Jackson?
Yeah.
I lost like $10,000 on loop ring.
All right.
Yes.
It's nothing.
Uh, but I also want you to explain why, not explain, but you know, tell us why are you
on a computer?
What's going on?
Yeah.
I'm curious.
Well, I had intended to come do the pod on the famous Bitcoin couch, uh, because that's
the energy that this pod is supposed to have.
Um, but this morning I woke up and my dog Pico was sick.
Pico is a six year old, uh, dog.
So he's generally super healthy and fun, but I woke up this morning and he had puked a
little bit overnight and they didn't want to eat his breakfast.
And I took him on a walk and he was pretty good during the walk, but then we came home
and he like half heartedly ate his breakfast.
And then he literally just like laid down in the middle of our hallway and he's been there
for the past five or six hours, just like lying there seeming really unwell.
And so I'm going to take him to that in an hour.
Um, I think he has like some kind of stomach trouble.
Like he's had this in the past, but he gets like really uncomfortable in his stomach and
then he wants to eat a lot of grass and then he pukes it up, but this one seems different.
He seems like really unwell.
So I'm actually very worried about him.
Um, so, you know, prayers to Pico, keep him in our hearts and minds.
Pico is gonna return to his full glory.
No doubts.
Yeah.
We're, we're pouring one out for Pico on the couch and yeah, no hate from, from the side
of the, of the computer.
I'm actually sitting, I'm like able to watch over him, but here he is right now.
He hasn't moved from right there in a couple of hours and he's just lying down, not feeling
good.
But say, Hey Pico, want to say hi?
Pico.
Oh, all right.
Oh man.
Very sad.
Very sad story.
He's going to be, he's going to be great.
Don't worry.
Good.
Yeah.
We'll do an update in the subsequent pond on Pico's health.
Pico update next week.
Yeah.
We'll note that down AI.
All right.
Let's see.
I think we will do maybe one more topic, maybe two more topics.
So next we'll do our deepest cut.
The most contrarian take on, on the crypto markets.
I'm going to get kicked out of the pond.
Yeah.
Chris looks like he's ready.
I'm going to get kicked out of the pond.
He's going to attack.
Sick.
Should I stop?
You seem the most ready.
Don't you?
I don't know.
I just, I feel like it's so bad that like anything that anyone else says is just going
to seem great by comparison.
Okay.
It's like a contrarian crypto thing, right?
Or like AI or like Bitcoin.
Yeah.
It could be AI if you really want it to be, but okay.
So this one might be a bit technical, but I think that like basically all stable coins
should go to zero in the limit.
Like I think they are the wrong instrument for like what people are trying to use them
for.
So like to, to like zoom out a little bit and give context, like the original definition
of a stable coin was, you know, this protocol die or ride and it was like a way for you
to arbitrarily peg values on chain to anything, right?
Something called a collateralized debt protocol.
So like, you know, a stable coin could be pegged to a dollar or it could be pegged to
a yen or it could be pegged to a big Mac, right?
So like the unit of value could be, could be anything, right?
The point is that it like remains stable in relation to this value.
And then somewhere along the way stable coin came to mean like a US dollar valued coin.
And then later it came to mean like a US dollar valued coin that is backed by US treasuries
and is redeemable by a centralized issuer, yada, yada, yada.
Yeah.
I think like, I think it's a great business model.
I think it's like a really interesting product.
I just think at some point, someone is going to come up with something that like blows it
away, both on passing yield back to the customers and like pushing things like the value of
money more towards the risk free rate, which is like the rate of short term treasury bills
and is like super vulnerable.
That's my update.
Okay.
But I don't know why do you think, why do you think that?
I just, I think like there's potential for a better product.
Like I think like, what's wrong with the product?
I mean, a good thing about it is that it's a US dollar.
A bad thing about it is that like it carries like issuer trust.
It carries.
So like, I think, you know, there was a recent occurrence with USDC where for the first time
in history, they froze a smart contract.
And they only do that due to a court order.
But my understanding is the court that ordered it was like, not, you know, it wasn't like
the US district court.
It was like a court.
So I think like, you know, with this like push pull about who can and can't do things,
it's going to get very complicated for these companies.
And the limit of what you can use that products for can only shrink, right?
It can't get, get bigger.
Whereas with some of these like more decentralized alternatives, like you can feel safe to use
it as, you know, the base layer for a protocol or whatever, you can't get like the mutants
court to like freeze your funds.
So you're, are you kind of saying that the stable coins being tied to like these fiat
currencies and therefore like inheriting regulations or getting regulations will, I don't know,
like strangle, strangle all the innovation out of stable coins and that you think there
will be some something else that can be innovated on, I don't know, outside of regulation.
Yeah, I think it's exactly I think it's two things.
I think one thing is like pegging it to a lossy fiat currency is one missed opportunity.
And then the other thing is like having it be backed by a corporation, which it's not
clear who they are accountable to, like it's not clear like legally, regulatory, who they're
accountable to, and like, you know, who like, like, no, there's never been an enforcement
on like a redemption schedule for a stable coin issuer that I'm aware of.
So there's just like a lot of like question marks about like, you know, what, like, what
can I use this for, like, if two courts are in conflict about like freezing something
like who takes preference, like, what does the company do, I don't know, I have a lot
of questions.
Yeah, that's my take.
But would we be allowed to use something that can't be controlled?
I mean, Bitcoin exists.
Yeah.
I mean, some people here own some of it.
Sorry.
I guess we are allowed to use Bitcoin.
Wow.
So you're like a closet Bitcoin maxi.
I'm a massive Bitcoin maxi.
As a stable coin.
Yeah.
Like, so everybody's like, Oh, is Chris the stablecoin guy?
Like he loves like T-bills and stuff.
No.
I mean, I, I don't, I don't know.
Okay.
Were you originally a stablecoin guy or you came at from ETH originally, right?
And then I feel like my vision of what I assumed was that you were like an Ether guy and that
you professionally were kind of pushed towards working on stablecoins because that's like
the main app on smart contract chains right now.
Yeah.
I would say I was more like a chain agnostic guy.
So the last place I worked, I was the Bitcoin guy and everyone else was like the mega ETH
guy.
But here, I think by virtue of like the Overton window, I am the ETH guy.
You're just a contrarian everywhere you go.
I just like to stir the pot 100%.
No, no home.
Wow.
Yeah.
This is lovely.
What a lovely take.
Do you think before we move on, do you think Bitcoin could be the, but what we eventually
get to or what like is this answer?
I do think that.
I think that we have to go through a lot of pain to get there.
Like I think like, you know, I think a lot of people think it's just going to be like,
we like get the rails there and like we work out something with scalability and then it's
just like going to be great.
I think it's going to be very sinusoidal, the path for us to get there.
And I think we're going to have to go through these other experiments like, yeah, Treasury
bill back to stable coins, collateralized debt protocols or something more capital efficient.
I think, yeah, I think it's going to be a long road, but I do.
I think like ultimately like the vision of Bitcoin is good and, and yeah, I think it's
like it would be a good outcome.
What timeline are you looking at or what time horizon do you see this playing out over?
And do you think like how different do you think Bitcoin is when this happens?
Like is it still lightning kind of dominated for payments or is there something else that
needs to come about for Bitcoin to be used in this censorship resistant or like free
way?
I, I really don't know.
I really don't know.
I think like my feeling is that something needs to be done with ZK provers so that can
be like independent L2s on Bitcoin.
And I think that's mainly because you can receive payments without having to service
a node in that way, like, which is great if you're like a company or like someone who's
really into it, but more difficult if you're just like person.
Yeah, I really don't know.
But I like, you know, the community is like super smart.
I'm sure like people, you know, people have been thinking about this forever, so there's
a lot smarter people than me with good ideas here.
But I think we're just going to have to like whiplash through this macro and like having
fable take my job and all these other things before we get there.
Okay.
Tyler, do you have any follow up questions or would you like to share your contrarian
take?
Chris, do you think that a like a sovereign stablecoin can be built that's collateralized
natively with crypto assets that's stable?
So I feel like that's kind of the holy grail and my understanding of the history of that
is that you had these algorithmic stablecoins like Luna is a good example where that was
like built with this model that clearly had this flaw and that flaw eventually reared
its head and it created a zero.
And so that's kind of like a dead end of the technology tree of stablecoins.
And then you have the stuff like Dai, for example, which is a sound model, but they
basically collateralized it with all of these centralized assets.
So to me, Dai is meaningless if it is majority collateralized by USDC, because then it's
like, well, then what do you, you're just wrapping USDC and calling it a sovereign asset,
like then circle controls Dai.
And then there are models where like you can, I guess instead of collateralizing it with
USDC, you can collateralize it with something like Ethereum or Bitcoin, and then it's kind
of more endogenous to the system, but then you have to put in more Bitcoin into that
system to over collateralize it, or more Ethereum into that system to over collateralize it
to make it safe.
And then it's like capital inefficient.
And it's like, who are the people that are providing the capital to back it?
And what are the incentives for them to make them do it?
And if it's capital inefficient, is that ever going to be something that they will choose
to do instead of putting their capital elsewhere?
So do you think that's an accurate like taxonomy of the crypto native type of stablecoin solutions?
And do you think that there can ever be a breakthrough for some of those problems?
Are people working on things that I'm not aware of?
Like what's your take there?
Because I think that space to me is much more interesting as like a crypto native kind of
sovereign stablecoin that doesn't have kind of physical dependencies in the real world,
yet that has been like the holy grail and I think it's eluded everyone.
Totally.
I completely agree with you on every point.
I think like, yeah, the collateral should be endogenous for like totally, totally obvious
reasons like that, you know, we were just talking about Circle being forced to free
something based on court order, like whether the court is from where or not the ambiguity
there.
And I also agree with you that I think like the one of the big issues with collateralized
debt protocols like DAI is capital inefficiency.
There's a project called Liquidy, which tries to get around it a little bit.
So instead of using the endogenous collateral, they use a staked version of it.
So the collateral is earning like two, 3% yield underneath, so it's not completely idle.
But obviously it doesn't really solve the problem of like, you know, that collateral
is not, that's not the risk free rate, right?
It's still lossy.
There are some other approaches.
So Athena is a stablecoin based on a delta neutral position.
So it holds a liquid restaking token on one end, which earns yield, and then a short position
on the other end.
And there's like an insurance fund that should pay out if it ever gets too far out of peg.
The short positions are on C5 exchanges, though, too, right?
Exactly.
There's no like sovereign place to do the short at that size.
And I think every time they try to like spin up a decentralized version of perps, I mean,
that's a whole separate discussion, right, whether that's like, you know, that exists
right now.
I mean, hyper liquid, right, bro, decentralized.
Like Jeff's three computers are doing like a lot of work, is what I will say.
I think recently, and I don't know if this is what you're alluding to, I think like Vitalik
released a paper, sort of proposing that you could build a stable instrument based on options.
So there's like a call option, you know, and like you basically split it into like a dollar
and then a remainder in the form of ETH and like rebalance by rolling it on an epoch.
I haven't read super deeply into that yet.
But I'm skeptical that it is like the golden bullet.
I think, you know, realistically, like that there's always going to be a compromise with
these types of instruments.
And I don't know if we'll ever find one that's like quite makes the trade offs that are the
same as, you know, like USDC or USDT or Prax or whatever.
That's my vibe.
Yeah.
Good vibe.
I appreciate that.
I was not alluding to the Vitalik thing, I had no idea.
I can't say I've ever made it past probably three sentences of a Vitalik blog post before
I thought there's no way I'm actually reading this whole thing and give up.
Yeah, so I mean, there's this thing called Fable that just came out that I've been, you
know, very appreciative of, able to like summarize.
So you need Fable level intelligence to like interpret the level of autism in the average
Vitalik blog post.
Look, if a jury can't understand meth, then like what chance do I have?
Did I ever tell you that I saw Vitalik in San Francisco?
No way.
Yeah.
And so I used to live in the mission right by where Cash App offices and I, because I
had lived in an apartment, I had to take Pico out to pee, like when he needed to pee.
And so I just was like, you know, threw on my Crocs, had like my, you know, like gym
shorts on, go downstairs, like a Saturday morning or something.
And I'm like, literally Pico is peeing outside of my front door and Vitalik just walks down
the sidewalk right past me.
And he's with like one other woman, I think.
And I was just like, what the fuck?
Like am I like hallucinating this?
Like there's no way this is real.
And obviously he's like one of the most, he looks very unique.
So he's like very recognizable.
And so I was like, screw it, I'm going to follow Vitalik.
So I like left my, you know, like I had like my keys in my pocket and so I took Pico and
we just followed him and he went right to Dolores Park.
And then it was very clear, like along the way, he picked up more people like me who
were like, holy shit, it's Vitalik, let's like see where he's going.
And he goes into Dolores Park and then it's kind of like pandemonium.
Like many people are recognizing him, they're running up, taking selfies and stuff.
Just yeah, Vitalik life, I guess.
He was also, he was wearing like a typical Vitalik outfit.
He was wearing like purple sweatpants, tight, like a weird purple shirt.
Like yeah, just looked like kind of disheveled and like a 13 year old or something.
I was going to ask you whether like you in your Crocs and basketball shorts or him had
like the benefit and it sounds like you've won, you've won that competition.
I think he had more Riz, you know, I'm just, he was looking like a guy who was just taking
his dog out to pee, you know, I was ready to be tailing, you know, international crypto
celebrity.
Yeah.
Nice.
That's a crazy story.
That's a good story.
Alright, actually given the time, maybe Kyler and I will save our contrarian takes and we'll
move into our last segment, which is the lottery tickets.
So Kyler, please take a look.
We're going to be scratching off.
These are some expensive ass lottery tickets.
No way.
Yeah.
Tyler, I know.
How much do they cost per ticket?
Five dollars?
Five dollars a pop.
Expanding.
We're going to scratch them with a 10 yen coin.
So Kyler, which, I mean, it's going to be weird for you.
One of us will scratch it for you, I guess.
Which one do you want for Pico?
I mean, I want the one with the heart, obviously, just because that's the only one I could save.
It also, it looks like by far the best art.
Damn it.
Okay.
That's why I got that one.
All right.
Sorry.
Here you go.
No, I respect that.
That one's too complicated for me.
Yeah.
It's obviously this is way too good.
I'm just simply not smart enough.
We'll start with Tyler.
Tyler, you got the cash crush.
I don't know if this is legal.
This is the cash crush card.
There's winning numbers and then our numbers.
So I'm going to just scratch the, or Chris, have you ever scratched a lottery ticket?
No, you go ahead.
Have you ever done it?
No, I'm Australian.
It's part of our cultural heritage.
Okay.
So you've done it before.
This is just a really elaborate mid-roll advertisement for the California state lottery.
Yeah.
We're sponsored by the California smart is so good.
Wow.
And they're expensive.
They'll get yours today.
In terms of like percentage points, is this like a better or worse investment than blueprint?
I think that's what you have to index it against.
Dude, I thought that I thought that you didn't have lottery tickets in the Australia.
So that's why I got some.
Oh dude, no.
Yeah, we love them.
We love them.
Oh shit.
So this is not a novel experience at all and I have to like learn how to play these seven
lines.
We should talk about Australia's gambling rules in the next quote.
I think that would be fascinating.
Yeah.
I think perps is on the, on the docket.
Okay, Tyler, I need you to interpret whether or not you want.
Can you read this?
I think we need Claude to make no mistakes on this.
I mean, I see $500.
I'm just going to assume that I won $500 and I'll take that ticket next time in the office.
Okay.
Wait, one thou.
I see the word one thou.
I see 250 thou.
That's so much money.
Could you screenshot this and tell Claude and upload it to Claude and get Claude to look
at it?
We can't even gamble on it.
Could you do that, Tyler?
Are you doing it?
Match any of your numbers for the five winning numbers, uncover an anchor, uncover a rose.
Here you go.
You can scratch them off.
I'm just going to start scratching because I have no idea how to spell.
So this one is going to be, this one's going to be awesome.
Cash Crush, yeah, sponsored by the California Lottery, Scratchers Cal Lottery, please send
your payment to me.
Jackson v. Cookin'.
Right.
This is the podcast discretionary.
Yeah I need to replenish my $15 that I spent on this podcast.
Right.
And then any access?
Todd says I won $6.
Whoa.
What?
Which really means that we won $1, right?
Because it was a $5 ticket.
Oh, no, dude, I think I think this one was an 11.
Is that right?
You think it got it wrong.
Yeah, sorry.
It does say 11, Claude thinks it's an 11.
My winning number is one of them is an 11.
Okay, yeah.
That's a one.
Oh, dang it.
Losing ticket for Tyler right there.
You wronged me.
I don't know what mine is either.
I got mine in Spanish.
I've got the Lotteria, Lotteria, Don Clemente.
Wait, what the fuck?
What the hell is going on?
Yeah, also, we tried to get some 40 ounce Colt 45 for the pod, but I went to four corner
stores in downtown Oakland and none of them had Colt 45, 40.
So if anyone knows where we can find those, send me a message.
You can find me on just a bunch of places.
You can find me.
I'm Jackson.
Also, Tyler, if you know, you should just tell me.
Dude, this one is straight up across the top.
I literally concrete.
I didn't like, I got you too complicated.
Yeah, this is insane.
I got La Corona.
We love that.
What does this mean?
I think you tested positive for COVID.
Scratch the collars cards and the one bonus.
Scratch the corresponding symbols on the Lotteria card.
Where's the Lotteria?
Match the collars card symbols.
Match all four symbols in the complete horizontal, vertical or diagonal line to win a prize.
Okay.
Do I have La Bandoline?
I do.
I have La Bandoline.
El Mufal.
I do not have El Mufal.
Damn it.
All right.
Do I have El Soul?
No, I don't.
Can you tell Claude to look at this one?
I mean, Claude didn't have a good track record on mine.
Yeah, but it's still better than me.
All right.
We're only on Opus 48 though.
Dude, put this on the page.
My Claude desktop doesn't have people yet leaving money on the table.
You know that, like, I've ever seen that meme from Rick and Morty where he makes the robot
and he's like, what is my purpose?
Your purpose is to move butter.
And it's like, oh my God.
That's what Claude is saying right now.
We're feeding it lotto tickets and asking it to verify who won.
Dude, we've all been earmarked for the permanent underclass.
We're never getting out.
Oh, man.
Claude refuses to say, I can't call for you with any confidence and I want to be straight
about why rather than guess.
Is it too complicated?
Claude can be kind of a pain in the ass sometimes.
Yeah.
It could be like a little bit too prudish.
Like literally the other night I woke up and my daughter had a fever.
And so it's like two a.m.
And we're trying to figure out how much Tylenol do we give a baby?
And the baby Tylenol package is like, talk to your doctor to get the dose.
And it's like, okay, it's two a.m.
I'm not going to talk to a doctor.
So then ask Claude.
And Claude was like, sorry, you really need to talk to your doctor.
And I was like, it's two a.m., bro, give it to me or else I'm just going to give her the
full bottle.
And I didn't even convince Claude and then I just googled it and there's like many websites
that are like, this is the ratio to take depending on your kid's age is like not helpful at all,
Claude.
It's like fables.
Godrails are really bad.
I don't know if you've had this experience.
Oh, it probably thought I was doing biomedical research by getting my six month old daughter
Tylenol.
Yeah.
That famous Eli Lilly project, that makes sense, man, mine's got a bonus on the back.
Sorry, guys.
I'm stoked right now.
How?
How do you have a bonus?
Okay.
I don't know.
I think like mine actually needs Claude.
Yeah, wait.
I got money.
Okay.
I'm rich, baby.
Match any of your cards to the winning card.
Win prize for that card.
I got six dollars, baby.
What?
El Arpa, which means heart and span.
I love that.
Fuck you.
I'm rich as hell.
All right.
Here you go.
No, dude.
See, I have to match these letters to these crosswords and I'm not doing that.
There's like no.
That's what Claude is.
There's no planet in which I'm doing that.
How do you, how do we feel about a crossword?
How does Claude feel?
Dude, that's insane.
That's insane.
Okay.
These are too complex, how they, how they expect the common man to decode ice.
Next time we'll just do these.
Right?
Yeah.
It has to be the like amount of attention required for a TikTok reel.
Anything more than that?
And I'm like, I'm cold.
But just plug it into your cloud when you get back.
We'll update the pod if Chris wants some money.
Next episode.
All right.
Thank you, everybody.
What's the name of our pod again?
The permanent under couch.
All right.
What's up, Todd?